<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<compendium>
  <version>1.0.3</version>
  <shapes zeroItemText="Du kennst noch keine Vorlagen! Unwissende sind nicht berechtigt dies zu lernen!">
    <shape id="Projectile">
      <name>Projektil</name>
      <desc>Du kannst nun deinen Willen zu einem konzentrierten Ball formen, den du von als Geschoss nutzen kannst.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>SPEED,GRAVITY,BOUNCE,DURATION,PIERCING,TARGET_NONSOLID_BLOCKS</modifiedBy>
    </shape>
    <shape id="Channel">
      <name>Kanalisiert</name>
      <desc>Through intense concentration, a mage can maintain a flow of magic on themselves.  This is useful for things like Telekinesis, Healing, Attract, and Storm.</desc>
      <modifiedBy></modifiedBy>
    </shape>
    <shape id="Beam">
      <name>Strahl</name>
      <desc>Es braucht nicht viele Mentale Veränderungen, um von einem Kanalisierten Zauberspruch zu einem Strahl, zu wechseln. Aber die Menge, der Belsatung, ist eine andere Geschichte. Ein Strahl ist eine besser kontrollierbare Version des kanalisierten Zauberspruchs!</desc>
      <modifiedBy>RANGE,TARGET_NONSOLID_BLOCKS</modifiedBy>
    </shape>
    <shape id="Self">
      <name>Selbst</name>
      <desc>Einer der einfachsten Formen, beim Anwenden von Magie, ist das Anwenden von Magie bei sich selber. Die Reichweite ist gering und das Ziel eindeutig. Du solltest nur hoffen, dass du dich nicht ausversehen selbst anzündest.</desc>
      <modifiedBy></modifiedBy>
    </shape>
    <shape id="Touch">
      <name>Berührung</name>
      <desc>Einfach gesagt, verbindet es deine Hand mit Magie. Somit braucht es direkten Kontakt zum Ziel.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>TARGET_NONSOLID_BLOCKS</modifiedBy>
    </shape>
    <shape id="Zone">
      <name>Zone</name>
      <desc>Du hast gelernt, deinen Willen auf eine auf einen Wirkungsbereich, der für eine bestimmte Zeit präsent sein wird, zu fokussieren.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>RADIUS,GRAVITY,DURATION</modifiedBy>
    </shape>
    <shape id="AoE">
      <name>Wirkungsbereich</name>
      <desc>Nachdem du deinen Zauberspruch aufgeladen hast, kannst du ihn in einen Stoß formen, der auswärts des Ursprungs ausgestrahl wird und einen Wirkunsbereich erzeugt(Dieser betrifft nicht den eigenen Spieler).</desc>
      <modifiedBy>RADIUS,GRAVITY</modifiedBy>
    </shape>
    <shape id="Chain">
      <name>Reihe</name>
      <desc>Du kannst deine Magie in einen Stoß formen, der von Ziel zu Ziel springt. Die Sprungweite kann mit den Modifikatoren #5Reichweite#0 erweitert und mit #5Proc#0 erhöht werden.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>RANGE,PROCS</modifiedBy>
    </shape>
    <shape id="Rune">
      <name>Rune</name>
      <desc>Du kannst eine magische Rune auf den Boden platzieren, die beim auslösen entweder starke Buffs...oder tötliche Fallen erzeugt.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>PROCS,TARGET_NONSOLID_BLOCKS</modifiedBy>
    </shape>
    <shape id="Contingency_Fall">
      <name>Vorkehrung: Fall</name>
      <desc>Du hast herausgefunden, wie man eine Zauberspruch-Vorlage erstellt, die nur etwas tut, wenn man runterfällt. !d Oh Gravitation, du bist so herzlos... !d Du kannst nur eine Vorkehrung zur selben Zeit verwenden.</desc>
      <modifiedBy></modifiedBy>
    </shape>
    <shape id="Contingency_Damage">
      <name>Vorkehrung: Schaden</name>
      <desc>Du hast herausgefunden, wie man einen Zauberspruch erstellt, der erst beschworen wird, wenn du verletzt wirst. !d Lasst uns 'Schuss für Schuss' spielen. !d Du kannst nur eine Vorkehrung zur selben Zeit verwenden.</desc>
      <modifiedBy></modifiedBy>
    </shape>
    <shape id="Contingency_Fire">
      <name>Vorkehrung: Feuer</name>
      <desc>Du hast dich dazu entschieden, nicht länger brennen zu können. Aus dem Grund hast du einen Zauberspruch, der nur 'aufleuchtet', wenn es das Feuer auch tut. !d Du kannst nur eine Vorkehrung zur selben Zeit verwenden.</desc>
      <modifiedBy></modifiedBy>
    </shape>
    <shape id="Contingency_Health">
      <name>Vorkehrung: Gesundheit</name>
      <desc>Egal wie fein der Zauberer auch ist, ein Messer zwischen den Schulterblättern zerstört echt seinen Stil. Du denkst, du hast einen Weg gefunden, der sie davon abhält das zu tun. Oder man nimmt einfach zwei Messer. !d Diese Vorkehrung wird erst aktiviert, wenn deine Gesundheit 25% oder geringer ist !d Du kannst nur eine Vorkehrung zur selben Zeit verwenden.</desc>
      <modifiedBy></modifiedBy>
    </shape>
    <shape id="Contingency_Death">
      <name>Vorkehrung: Tod</name>
      <desc>Du kriegst mich vielleicht, aber in diesen Paar Sekunden wird es dich kriegen...Und ich habe alle Zeit der Welt, um dir das zu versichern. !d Du kannst nur eine Vorkehrung zur selben Zeit verwenden.</desc>
      <modifiedBy></modifiedBy>
    </shape>
    <shape id="Binding">
      <name>Bindung</name>
      <desc>Du kannst solide Objekte aus dem Nichts erschaffen! Die 'Bindung-Vorlage' erlaubt es dir Werkzeuge/Waffen mit dir zu binden. Es verringert die konstante Mana, solange es gebunden ist. Und es verbraucht Mana bei der Verwendung, im Tausch mit Haltbarkeit. Das Droppen des Werkzeugs (standartmäßig mit 'Q') wird die Bindung wieder aufheben.</desc>
      <modifiedBy></modifiedBy>
      <relatedEntries>bindingCatalyst@0,bindingCatalyst@1,bindingCatalyst@2,bindingCatalyst@3,bindingCatalyst@4,bindingCatalyst@5</relatedEntries>
    </shape>
    <shape id="Wall">
      <name>Wand</name>
      <desc>Du kannst eine Wand vor dir erschaffen, diese ist eigentlich das selbe, wie eine #5Zone#0, allerdings anders im dargestellten Aufbau. Abgesehen davon kann sie ihre Effekte schneller anwenden als die #5Zone#0</desc>
      <modifiedBy>RADIUS,GRAVITY,DURATION</modifiedBy>
    </shape>
    <shape id="Wave">
      <name>Welle</name>
      <desc>Erschaffe eine magische Welle, die auf ihrem Weg vorwärts alles mit ihrem Effekt ansteckt(z.B: Feuerschaden).</desc>
      <modifiedBy>RADIUS,DURATION,SPEED,GRAVITY,PIERCING</modifiedBy>
    </shape>
  </shapes>
  <components zeroItemText="You don't know any components yet, and aren't eligible to learn any!">
    <component id="PhysicalDamage">
      <name>Physischer Schaden</name>
      <desc>Oft beginnt das Training eines jungen Magiers mit einfacher physischer Gewalt, wie Boxen. Häufiger geht das Training dann mit mehr psysischer Gewalt weiter.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>DAMAGE</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="MagicDamage">
      <name>Magieschaden</name>
      <desc>Magieschaden ist anders als physischer Schaden, in der Tatsache, dass es viele Arten von Rüstung umgeht und somit die Aura des Ziels direkt beschädigt. Was letzten Endes genauso verheerend sein kann, wenn nicht sogar mehr. Dies ist bei beschworen Kreaturen besonders anfällig</desc>
      <modifiedBy>DAMAGE</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="FrostDamage">
      <name>Frostschaden</name>
      <desc>Viele unterschätzen die Stärke, die Frost beinhalten kann. Die schleichende Kälte can viele Rüstungen umgehen. Außerdem ist es besonders effiktiv gegen die Bewohner des Nethers.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>DAMAGE,BUFF_POWER</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="LightningDamage">
      <name>Blitzschaden</name>
      <desc>Ich hield meine Hände vor mir und mit einem lauten Knall kam ein großartiger weißer Blitz den Himmel entlang. Seine eiserne Rüstung war wie ein Blitzableiter, somit drang jeder Blitz in ihn ein. Blitzschaden macht imensen Schaden, dafür kostet es SEHR VIEL Mana.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>DAMAGE</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="FireDamage">
      <name>Feuerschaden</name>
      <desc>Mit nur einem Wort lies ich meinem Willen frei und ein Feuer aus dem Nichts war vor mir. Es hat alles gebraten, was im Weg des Feuers war. !l Beachte: Es macht zwar viel Schaden, aber Nether-Mobs sind immun gegen Feuer(schaden).</desc>
      <modifiedBy>DAMAGE</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Ignition">
      <name>Entzündung</name>
      <desc>Viele Magier sehen Feuer als eine schadene, destruktive macht, was sogar wahr sein kann. Aber wie viele, die das Wort 'Feuer' hören, stellen sich vor, wie man einen Ofen, ein Lagerfeuer oder eine Kerze anzündet?</desc>
      <modifiedBy>DURATION</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Forge">
      <name>Schmelzen</name>
      <desc>Du hast nun die feine Kontrolle über Feuer und kannst somit Blöcke, wie sie in ihrer Form da stehen, schmelzen, ohne sie gleich in Asche zu verwandeln..</desc>
      <modifiedBy></modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Blind">
      <name>Blenden</name>
      <desc>Einen Feuerball zu haben, den man auf dunkle Magier werfen kann, ist einfach toll. Es zu machen sorgt dafür das sie das Wesentliche nicht sehen können.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>BUFF_POWER,DURATION</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Freeze">
      <name>Einfrieren</name>
      <desc>Eira atmete tief ein und öffnete ihre Augen. Die Spitzen der Berge waren nun weiß, mit Schnee und Frost bedekt. Wasser wurde zu Eis. Nichts hat sich bewegt. Perfekt.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>BUFF_POWER,DURATION</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Knockback">
      <name>Rückstoß</name>
      <desc>Nicht viele Magier wollen in Reichweite einer Nahkampfattacke sein. Dies erlaubt es dir das auch beizubehalten.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>VELOCITY_ADDED</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Storm">
      <name>Gewitter</name>
      <desc>Der Himmel verdunkelte sich und es begann zu regnen. Der Wind heulte und ein Blitz war am Himmel zu sehen. Der Sturm war ohrenbetäubend. Die Blitze schlugen in meine Feinde neben mir ein. Es war eine enorme Belastung für mich, denn der Sturm war imens.</desc>
      <modifiedBy></modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="AstralDistortion">
      <name>Astrale Verzerrung</name>
      <desc>Als ich versuchte einen Fuß in die Leere zu setzen, bemerkte ich, dass die Kette schimmerte und sich zu verfestigen scheint. Ich ging mit dem Gesicht vorraus hinein. Ich musst es doch auch gegen die Endermen einsetzen können.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>BUFF_POWER,DURATION</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Fling">
      <name>Werfen</name>
      <desc>Der Wind wirbelte unter den Creeper und endlich explodierte er. Und er wurde endlich gen Himmel gesendet.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>VELOCITY_ADDED</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="WateryGrave">
      <name>Wässernes Grab</name>
      <desc>Das Wasser wurde anscheinend lebending und wickelte sich um den Lichtmagier und zog ihn runter in die dunklen Tiefen des Meeres.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>BUFF_POWER,DURATION</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Leap">
      <name>Sprung</name>
      <desc>Der Wind umgab mich und ich begann abzuheben. Ich hielt den Wind nahe beim Sprung, um einen Windstoß zu erzeugen, der mich in die Luft beförderte. Beim Landen war der Wind wie ein Kissen, dass mich vor dem Fall schützte.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>BUFF_POWER,DURATION</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Regeneration">
      <name>Regeneration</name>
      <desc>Ich hielt meinen Arm in ein heilendes Licht und ich sah zu, wie jede Verletzung langsam aber sicher vor meinen Augen verschwand.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>BUFF_POWER,DURATION</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Slowfall">
      <name>Langsames Fallen</name>
      <desc>Werde leicht wie eine Feder und habe keine Angst mehr vorm Fallen.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>BUFF_POWER,DURATION</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="LifeTap">
      <name>Leben anzapfen</name>
      <desc>Wenn ein Magier verzweifelt ist und ihm das Mana ausgeht, kann er diesen Spruch benutzen um Leben gegen Kraft zu tauschen.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>DAMAGE</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Heal">
      <name>Heilung</name>
      <desc>Bei schwindender Kraft kann ein Magier sich regenerieren. DAS ist 'erste Hilfe'!</desc>
      <modifiedBy>HEALING</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Slow">
      <name>Verlangsamen</name>
      <desc>Bei schwindender Kraft kann ein Magier sich regenerieren. Somit kann ein Magier sich selbst wieder zusammenflicken.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>BUFF_POWER,DURATION</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Haste">
      <name>Eile</name>
      <desc>Ein Magier kann die Bewegungen deutlich verschnellern, indem er die Beine seines Ziels in arkaner Energie verpackt.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>BUFF_POWER,DURATION</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="GravityWell">
      <name>Schwerkraftschacht</name>
      <desc>Du hast herausgefunden, wie man einen Schwerkraftschaft unter einem Ziel beschwört. Dieser erhöht die Fallgeschwindigkeit des Ziels imens.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>BUFF_POWER,DURATION</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="LifeDrain">
      <name>Leben Entziehen</name>
      <desc>Beim Beschwören einer Verbindung zu deines Ziels Lebensquell, kann diese angezapft und für sich selbst verwendet werden.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>DAMAGE</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Dispel">
      <name>Vertreiben</name>
      <desc>Das Erzeugen eines magischen Feldes, kann deinem Ziel einige Effekte vertreiben.  Außerdem vertreibt es beschworene Kreaturen ins Ether..</desc>
      <modifiedBy></modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Repel">
      <name>Abstoßen</name>
      <desc>Du kannst nun eine Singularität ins All schießen, die solange du dich auf sie konzentrierst, ein Kraftfeld erzeugt, das Gegner und Pfeile zurückwirft.</desc>
      <modifiedBy></modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="SwiftSwim">
      <name>Schnelles Schwimmen</name>
      <desc>Das Manipulieren von Wasserströmen, bringt dich schneller im Wasser vorran.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>BUFF_POWER,DURATION</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Levitate">
      <name>Aufsteigen</name>
      <desc>Das verwenden von Luftmagie, kann dich in die Luft befördern. Mit nur geringen Luftströmen kannst du dich langsam zu Boden gleiten lassen..</desc>
      <modifiedBy>BUFF_POWER,DURATION</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="ManaDrain">
      <name>Mana entziehen</name>
      <desc>Du kannst nun parasitäre Fesseln an der Aura deines Feindes anbringen, diese entziehen dem Ziel Mana und geben es dir.</desc>
      <modifiedBy></modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Entangle">
      <name>Einwickeln</name>
      <desc>Auf dein Kommando kannst du Ranken beschwören, die dein Ziel fesseln und es bewegungsunfähig machen.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>BUFF_POWER,DURATION</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Flight">
      <name>Flug</name>
      <desc>Mit nur einem Wort hob ich ab. Ich fühlte mich schnell und agil. Der Himmel gehörte mir allein.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>BUFF_POWER,DURATION</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Shield">
      <name>Schild</name>
      <desc>Du kannst ein Schild aus arkaner Energie erzeugen. Dieses wird deinen Schaden drastisch reduzieren.  Dies kann nicht zur selben Zeit mit #5Reflektieren#0 verwendet werden.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>BUFF_POWER,DURATION</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Reflect">
      <name>Reflektieren</name>
      <desc>Du kannst nun ein Schild kreieren, dass Dinge Abprallen lässt und sie somit keinen Schaden verursachen. Dies kann nicht zur selben Zeit mit #5Schild#0 verwendet werden.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>BUFF_POWER,DURATION</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="ChronoAnchor">
      <name>Chrono-Anker</name>
      <desc>Du kannst dich zeitweise verankern. Sobald der Timer abläuft, wirst du wieder zurück an diese Stelle mit deiner Gesundheit, deinem Mana, deiner Erschöpfung und Hunger(Speichert die Werte und hält sie sobald der Zauber gesprochen wurde), gebracht.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>BUFF_POWER,DURATION</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Charm">
      <name>Charme</name>
      <desc>Mit deinem Charme kannst du Kreaturen dazu bringen, für dich zu kämpfen und bestimmte Kreaturen tun dann auch bestimmte Sachen. Außerdem kannst du damit Tiere zum paaren bringen.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>BUFF_POWER,DURATION</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Dig">
      <name>Graben</name>
      <desc>Der Boden fängt mit nur einem Schnips an zu zittern und je härter der Block ist, desto mehr Mana wird benötigt. Kann mit dem Modifikator #5Abbau Stärke#0 auf Diamant verbessert werden.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>MINING_POWER,FORTUNE_LEVEL,SILKTOUCH_LEVEL</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Light">
      <name>Licht</name>
      <desc>Du kannst mittels Magie einen Bereich erleuchten.  Rechtklick mit einem Farbstoff, ändert ihre Farbe.  'Forge Ore Directory' übernimmt die meisten Farbstoffe aus anderen Mods.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>COLOR</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Disarm">
      <name>Entwaffnung</name>
      <desc>Jetzt da du du gelernt hast, Werkzeuge aus dem Nichts in deine Hand zu zaubern, ist es nur noch einen Schritt vom Entwaffnen deiner Gegner entfernt.</desc>
      <modifiedBy></modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Rift">
      <name>Spalt</name>
      <desc>Du kannst nun einen Spalt öffnen, der dir Zugang zu einer Dimension verschafft, in der du deine Sachen lagern kannnst.  Der Spalt bleibt für 60 Sek offen, bis er sich von alleine wieder schließt.  Buff Stärke Modifikatoren erhöhen den Speicherplatz.  Schleichen + Rechtsklick schließt einen offenen Spalt.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>BUFF_POWER</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Attract">
      <name>Anziehen</name>
      <desc>Du kannst nun ein Gebiet mit negativem Druck, um dich herum, erzeugen. Es zieht alles Lebende zu dir</desc>
      <modifiedBy></modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Telekinesis">
      <name>Telekinese</name>
      <desc>Du kannst Magie verwenden, um deinen Gehirnwellen eine physikalische Fähigkeit zu geben.  Diese Ströme können Items und XP zu einem bestimmten Punkt ziehen.  Schleichen und das Rollen, des Mausrads, ändert die Distanz des Punktes.</desc>
      <modifiedBy></modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="HarvestPlants">
      <name>Pflanzen ernten</name>
      <desc>Du kannst alle Blätter, Pflanzen und Blumen dazu bringen, sich zu ernten.</desc>
      <modifiedBy></modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Plow">
      <name>Pflügen</name>
      <desc>Du kannst die Erde auf dein Kommando zum aufwühlen bringen. Perkeft um Tiefe Fugen fürs Pflanzen zu machen.</desc>
      <modifiedBy></modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="CreateWater">
      <name>Wasser kreieren</name>
      <desc>Du kannst die Feuchtigkeit in der Luft an eine Position setzen. Das erzeugen von Wasser ist ja nun wirklich keine Herausforderung...  Dieser Spruch funktioniert nicht im Nether.  Kessel können damit befüllt werden.</desc>
      <modifiedBy></modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Grow">
      <name>Wachsen</name>
      <desc>Das Leiten von Energie in Pflanzen lässt sie schneller wachsen, als Monate langes reden.</desc>
      <modifiedBy></modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="BanishRain">
      <name>Regen verbannen</name>
      <desc>Regen Regen, breche ab.  Komme wieder an einem and'ren Tag!  Wer hätte gedacht, dass das die Worte zu diesem Zauber wären?  Wenn man es mit dem entsprechenden Ritual macht, kann man Regen auch beschwören.  Betrachte die #5Ritual#0 Seite, für weitere Details.</desc>
      <modifiedBy></modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="WaterBreathing">
      <name>Unterwasseratmung</name>
      <desc>Du kannst deine Magie dazu verwenden, Sauerstoff aus dem Wasser zu entziehen. dies erlaubt es dir für eine gewisse Zeit nicht zu ertrinken.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>BUFF_POWER,DURATION</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="NightVision">
      <name>Nachtsicht</name>
      <desc>Dein Wissen über Licht, erlaubt es dir im Dunklen zu seh'n.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>BUFF_POWER,DURATION</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="TrueSight">
      <name>Wahre Sicht</name>
      <desc>Deine 'magische Sicht' erlaubt es dir Dinge zu sehen, die du normalerweise nicht siehst. Wer weiß schon wie's wirklich ist? Naja, du auf jeden Fall!</desc>
      <modifiedBy>BUFF_POWER,DURATION</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Invisibility">
      <name>Unsichtbarkeit</name>
      <desc>Du kannst das Licht um dich herum so brechen, dass du praktisch unsichtbar bist.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>BUFF_POWER,DURATION</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="RandomTeleport">
      <name>Zufälliger Teleport</name>
      <desc>Du kannst dein Ziel, in einem kleinen Radius darum, an einen zufälligen Ort teleportieren.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>RANGE</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Blink">
      <name>Blenden</name>
      <desc>Du kannst dich ein kleines Bisschen in die Richtung deines Blickfeldes teleportieren.  Es kann dich auch durch Wände bringen, aber wir versichern dir, dass du in keiner stecken bleibst.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>RANGE</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Transplace">
      <name>Translokieren</name>
      <desc>Dein Wissen über Teleportation wurde erweitert. Du kannst nun die Plätze mit deinem Ziel tauschen.</desc>
      <modifiedBy></modifiedBy>
	  <relatedEntries>rituals_overview,otherworldly_ritual</relatedEntries>
    </component>
    <component id="Mark">
      <name>Markieren</name>
      <desc>Du kannst eine gewisse Position markieren, zu der du jeder Zeit zurückkehren kannst.</desc>
      <modifiedBy></modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Recall">
      <name>Rückruf</name>
      <desc>Du kannst hiermit an deine markierte Stelle zurückkehren.</desc>
      <modifiedBy></modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="EnderIntervention">
      <name>Ender-Intervention</name>
      <desc>You have mastered teleportation magic, to the level at which you can transcend interdimensional barriers, and can enter the nether from almost anywhere.</desc>
      <modifiedBy></modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="DivineIntervention">
      <name>Göttliche Intervention</name>
      <desc>Du bist jetzt Meister der Teleportationsmagie. Somit kannst du interdimensionale Barrieren erzeugen mit denen du von überall die Oberwelt betreten kannst. Bist du schon an der Oberwelt, kehrst du zu deinem Bett oder Spawn zurück.</desc>
      <modifiedBy></modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Summon">
      <name>Summon</name>
      <desc>You have learned to harvest the souls of creatures you defeat in combat.  These souls can be used in creating a spell to summon that creature to protect you. !d To summon a creature, first craft a #5Crystal Phylactery#0.  Once you kill something while holding an empty phylactery, that phylactery will become #9attuned#0 to that specific mob.  Kill enough of the same mob and you will fill the phylactery. !d During spell creation, you can throw in any filled phylactery when prompted by the lectern.  This step is what determines what your spell will summon. !d Summoned creatures drop no loot, and no xp, but can be interacted with normally, such as breeding, milking cows, or riding horses.  Horses are the exception to the item drop rule and will drop saddles and armor given to them. !l Tameable creatures such as wolves and cats are automatically tamed to their owner upon summoning. !d Bosses cannot be trapped in phylacteries in survival/adventure mode. </desc>
      <modifiedBy>DURATION</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Blizzard">
      <name>Blizzard</name>
      <desc>You have learned to summon a fearsome blizzard, which will slow and damage any entities in its radius.  Blizzard has a built-in AoE to it.  A blizzard cannot be summoned within 5 blocks of another existing blizzard.  It initially does less damage than other attacks, but scales more quickly with modifiers.  It also has the unique capability to deal damage more often than regular attacks. Though blizzard will harm all entities in its radius, it will never harm its caster.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>RADIUS,DAMAGE,DURATION</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Daylight">
      <name>Daylight</name>
      <desc>You have gained the ability to control time.  This spell will cause the time to move to Dawn.</desc>
      <modifiedBy></modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="FallingStar">
      <name>Starstrike</name>
      <desc>You can call down a star from the skies and cause it to strike all entities within the blast radius.  It will harm friendly targets but not the caster.  There is a short delay between casting the spell and the impact.  This spell will not work underground (the star will fall onto the surface).</desc>
      <modifiedBy>DAMAGE</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="FireRain">
      <name>Firestorm</name>
      <desc>You have learned to summon a terrible firestorm, which will do large amounts of damage any entities in its radius.  Firestorm has a built-in AoE to it.  A firestorm cannot be summoned within 5 blocks of another existing firestorm.  It initially does less damage than other attacks, but scales more quickly with modifiers.  It also has the unique capability to deal damage more often than regular attacks.  Firestorm does not ignite the ground.  Though firestorm will harm all entities in its radius, it will never harm its caster.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>RADIUS,DAMAGE,DURATION</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="ManaLink">
      <name>Mana Link</name>
      <desc>You have discovered the secret to linking your mana together with another entity.  When you cast this spell, your target will be able to draw upon your mana pool as if it were their own. !d The target will use their own mana first, then will begin to draw upon yours. !d It has a limited radius, but can have radius modifiers if you so desire.  If the target leaves the radius, the link is not broken, but is rather temporarily disabled.  When they again return into the radius, the link will reactivate and will function again.  To end the link, simply cast the spell on the target again. !d You can link your own mana to multiple entities, and on the other side, you can have multiple links coming in from other sources.</desc>
      <modifiedBy></modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="ManaShield">
      <name>Mana Shield</name>
      <desc>Your target becomes shielded by their available mana, causing damage to drain 250 mana per half heart absorbed, and preventing HP damage entirely.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>DURATION,BUFF_POWER</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Moonrise">
      <name>Moonrise</name>
      <desc>You have gained the ability to control time.  This spell will cause the time to move to Dusk.</desc>
      <modifiedBy></modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Drought">
      <name>Drought</name>
      <desc>You have taken your knowledge of creating water and have reversed the process.  This spell will draw water out of whatever it hits, removing water blocks and turning dirt, grass, sandstone and mycelium to sand, withering plants it hits, and stone to cobblestone.</desc>
      <modifiedBy></modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Plant">
      <name>Plant</name>
      <desc>You can cause seeds from your inventory to be planted in the ground, if conditions are right for it to grow.  Best coupled with AoE or some other such shape for rapid planting.</desc>
      <modifiedBy></modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Accelerate">
      <name>Accelerate</name>
      <desc>This spell causes targeted blocks to tick faster.  Note that it does not make tile entities any quicker.  This spell is best used in a shape like beam, wall, or zone, due to its need to be cast multiple times to have any real effect.</desc>
      <modifiedBy></modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Drown">
      <name>Drown</name>
      <desc>You can create water directly inside the target's lungs, causing them to take drowning damage.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>DAMAGE</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="WizardsAutumn">
      <desc>You have learned to focus your digging magic into a small radius that directly affects leaves.  This component has a built in AoE that can be modified with Radius modifiers.  You can use it to clear those pesky hard to reach leaves.</desc>
      <name>Wizard's Autumn</name>
      <modifiedBy>RADIUS</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Fury">
      <name>Fury</name>
      <desc>You can send yourself into an absolute rage, dealing increased damage, moving extremely fast, passively regenerating, and mining at inhuman speeds.  When the effect ends, you are left exhausted for a few moments and must recover.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>DURATION,BUFF_POWER</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Appropriation">
      <name>Appropriation</name>
      <desc>You can appropriate one block or entity into your spell.  Casting the spell again will place a picked up entity or block at the targeted location.</desc>
      <modifiedBy></modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Silence">
      <name>Silence</name>
      <desc>You can silence another entity, preventing all spell casting for a short duration.  THe duration cannot be extended.</desc>
      <modifiedBy></modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="Shrink">
      <name>Shrink</name>
      <desc>You can make yourself tiny!  When this effect is active, you are physically smaller, so you can fit through 1x1 gaps.  Due to your light weight, you fall slowly enough that landing doesn't hurt either.  However, all damage you do is halved.</desc>
      <modifiedBy>DURATION,BUFF_POWER</modifiedBy>
    </component>
    <component id="PlaceBlock">
      <name>Place Block</name>
      <desc>You can use this spell part to place blocks!  Can be extremely powerful when combined with different shape combinations.  In order to place a block, you need to set the spell to place it, and you need to have at least one of said block in your inventory.  No creating them out of thin air, sorry!  To set the block to be placed, cast the spell on a block while sneaking.  You need to be sneaking when the spell actually applies, so keep that in mind when using something like Projectile.  It's recommended to not use AoE to set the block, as it can sometimes set it to something you don't expect (as it will apply to everything in a radius, setting the block over and over).  To see what block the spell will place, hover your mouse over it in your inventory and press SHIFT.</desc>
      <modifiedBy></modifiedBy>
    </component>
  </components>
  <modifiers zeroItemText="You don't know any modifiers yet, and aren't eligible to learn any!">
    <modifier id="Gravity">
      <name>Gravity</name>
      <desc>Amplifies the gravity of certain spell shapes.  Zones and projectiles will be affected by gravity.  AoE spells will search farther down when applying to terrain for a valid spot to apply (this is useful as it causes it to hug the terrain).</desc>
      <modifies>GRAVITY</modifies>
    </modifier>
    <modifier id="Bounce">
      <name>Bounce</name>
      <desc>Causes the projectile spell shape to bounce off surfaces.</desc>
      <modifies>BOUNCE</modifies>
    </modifier>
    <modifier id="Damage">
      <name>Damage</name>
      <desc>Amplifies the damage dealt by spells.</desc>
      <modifies>DAMAGE</modifies>
    </modifier>
    <modifier id="Healing">
      <name>Healing</name>
      <desc>Amplifies the healing done by spells, or the damage dealt by healing spells to the undead.</desc>
      <modifies>HEALING</modifies>
    </modifier>
    <modifier id="Speed">
      <name>Speed</name>
      <desc>Enhances the speed altering effects of spells, and the speed of projectiles.</desc>
      <modifies>SPEED</modifies>
    </modifier>
    <modifier id="Duration">
      <name>Duration</name>
      <desc>Enhances the duration of all buff/debuff effects, and increases the duration of zones.</desc>
      <modifies>DURATION</modifies>
    </modifier>
    <modifier id="Range">
      <name>Range</name>
      <desc>Increases the range of projectile and beam spells.</desc>
      <modifies>RANGE</modifies>
    </modifier>
    <modifier id="Radius">
      <name>Radius</name>
      <desc>Increases the radius of zone and AoE spell shapes.</desc>
      <modifies>RADIUS</modifies>
    </modifier>
    <modifier id="RuneProcs">
      <name>Rune Procs</name>
      <desc>Increases the number of times a rune can apply it's effect before being destroyed.</desc>
      <modifies>PROCS</modifies>
    </modifier>
    <modifier id="VelocityAdded">
      <name>Velocity Added</name>
      <desc>Increases the amount of velocity added by spell parts such as #5Fling#0.</desc>
      <modifies>VELOCITY_ADDED</modifies>
    </modifier>
    <modifier id="TargetNonSolid">
      <name>Target Non-Solid Blocks</name>
      <desc>Allows the spell to target non-solid blocks (grass, water, lava) rather than passing through it.</desc>
      <modifies>TARGET_NONSOLID_BLOCKS</modifies>
    </modifier>
    <modifier id="Lunar">
      <name>Lunar</name>
      <desc>Powers up your spell at night.  The closer to midnight time is (Starting at Dusk), the more damage and healing the spell does.  After midnight, as dawn approaches, the spell will become weaker.  Range, Duration, and Radius are all increased where applicable based on the phase of the moon (more power approaching full moon).  More powerful than Solar due to nights not lasting as long as day.</desc>
      <modifies>DAMAGE,HEALING,RANGE,RADIUS,DURATION</modifies>
    </modifier>
    <modifier id="Solar">
      <name>Solar</name>
      <desc>Powers up your spell during the day.  The closer to noon time is (Starting at Dawn), the more damage and healing the spell does.  After noon, as dusk approaches, the spell will become weaker.  Range, Duration, and Radius are all increased where applicable based on the phase of the moon (more power approaching new moon).</desc>
      <modifies>DAMAGE,HEALING,RANGE,RADIUS,DURATION</modifies>
    </modifier>
    <modifier id="Piercing">
      <name>Piercing</name>
      <desc>Allows the spell to pierce through entities and blocks.  2 pierces are added per modifier, with a maximum of 6.</desc>
      <modifies>PIERCING</modifies>
    </modifier>
    <modifier id="MiningPower">
      <name>Mining Power</name>
      <desc>You have learned to put more power into your digging spells.  This causes them to be able to dig more dense blocks that would require a better pickaxe.  Each modifier bumps the spell up by one tool level.  The base Dig spell operates at Stone pickaxe mining level.</desc>
      <modifies>MINING_POWER</modifies>
    </modifier>
    <modifier id="Prosperity">
      <name>Prosperity</name>
      <desc>Fortune strikes!  You can make your digging spells more likely to drop additional ores, and your damaging spells more likely to cause enemies to drop better loot.  Each modifier added is equivalent to one level of fortune/looting on the spell.</desc>
      <modifies>FORTUNE_LEVEL</modifies>
    </modifier>
    <modifier id="BuffPower">
      <name>Buff Power</name>
      <desc>You can put more power into your buffs.  Each modifier added increases the level of the buff applied.  This will not affect duration.</desc>
      <modifies>BUFF_POWER</modifies>
    </modifier>
    <modifier id="Dismembering">
      <name>Dismembering</name>
      <desc>You've decided that you like souvenirs.  So much so, that you have discovered how to make your damaging spells leave some pieces intact.  Each modifier adds 5% chance to drop a head when defeating an enemy.</desc>
      <modifies>DISMEMBERING_LEVEL</modifies>
    </modifier>
    <modifier id="FeatherTouch">
      <name>Feather Touch</name>
      <desc>With great power comes broken valuables.  You've learned to be more careful when casting your digging spells and break things less often.  Each modifier is equivalent to one level of Silk Touch on the spell.</desc>
      <modifies>SILKTOUCH_LEVEL</modifies>
    </modifier>
  </modifiers>
  <talents zeroItemText="You don't know any talents yet, and aren't eligible to learn any!">
    <talent id="AffinityGains">
      <name>Affinity Gains Boost</name>
      <desc>You have decided that elemental attunement is more important than arcane knowledge.  You can receive a boost to affinity gains in exchange for slower magic XP gain.  This is a permanent effect.</desc>
    </talent>
    <talent id="AugmentedCasting">
      <name>Augmented Casting</name>
      <desc>You have figured out how to put everything you have into a spell cast.  All of your spells are more powerful.  Durations are longer, radii are bigger, and damage is increased.</desc>
    </talent>
    <talent id="ExtraSummon">
      <name>Extra Summon</name>
      <desc>Why do things yourself when you can have others do them for you?  You can now have one additional summoned/charmed creature or recruited mage (if you have the #5Mage Posse#0 talent)</desc>
    </talent>
    <talent id="MageBandI">
      <name>Mage Posse I</name>
      <desc>Your talents as a mage have impressed others, and your reputation precedes you.  You can request that a light mage follow and guard you.  This counts against your summon cap.</desc>
    </talent>
    <talent id="MageBandII">
      <name>Mage Posse II</name>
      <desc>You have gained the trust of other mages to the point that they feel safe linking their magic to yours.  Whenever you befriend a light mage, they will mana link to you.</desc>
    </talent>
    <talent id="ManaRegenI">
      <name>Mana Regen Boost I</name>
      <desc>You are more attuned with the energy flowing through you.  Your magic regenerates slightly faster than normal.</desc>
    </talent>
    <talent id="ManaRegenII">
      <name>Mana Regen Boost II</name>
      <desc>You are more attuned with the energy flowing through you.  Your magic regenerates faster than normal.  This replaces the bonus given by Mana Regen Boost I.</desc>
    </talent>
    <talent id="ManaRegenIII">
      <name>Mana Regen Boost III</name>
      <desc>You are more attuned with the energy flowing through you.  Your magic regenerates much faster than normal. This replaces the bonus given by Mana Regen Boost II.</desc>
    </talent>
    <talent id="SpellMotion">
      <name>Spell Movement</name>
      <desc>You have realized that agility is key.  To that end, you have trained yourself to be able to move at normal speed while using a spell.</desc>
    </talent>
    <talent id="Colour">
      <name>Colour</name>
      <desc>This modifier allows you to change the color of the particles on your spell.  Want green fireballs?  Have at it!  Color is determined by the color dye that you throw in during the crafting process.  Any one will be accepted, regardless of what the lectern prompts for.</desc>
    </talent>
  </talents>
  <items>
    <item id="ores">
      <name>AM Ores</name>
      <desc>Ars Magica adds a few new ores to the game that you will need to collect and refine.</desc>
      <subitem id="itemOre@0">
        <name>Vinteum Dust</name>
        <desc>Discovered in a small village where a creeper was knocked down a drained well, Vinteum Ore was quickly realized to be a valuable magical powder once cooked inside a furnace.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>ores@0,calefactor,vinteumTorch</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="itemOre@1">
        <name>Arcane Compound</name>
        <desc>A combination of materials from multiple worlds, the Arcane Compound forms the base resource needed to get Arcane Ash.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>itemOre@2,calefactor</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="itemOre@2">
        <name>Arcane Ash</name>
        <desc>Created by burning #5Arcane Compounds#0 in a furnace, Arcane Ash's Etherium storage capabilities have made it a cornerstone of advanced magical machinery.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>itemOre@1,calefactor</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="itemOre@3">
        <name>Purified Vinteum Dust</name>
        <desc>By adding #5Arcane Ash#0 to strengthen its magical properties, and adding #5Blue Orchids#0 as a catalyst and #5Desert Novas#0 to release instability, Vinteum Dust can be put into a purified state with much higher capacity for Etherium.</desc>
        <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="itemOre@4">
        <name>Chimerite</name>
        <desc>Able to shift to all colors and in an ever-changing state, Chimerite is used in spells that require a great deal of alteration or illusion.</desc>
        <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="itemOre@5">
        <name>Blue Topaz</name>
        <desc>A relatively common gem, blue topaz is often used by mages as an entry level crystal to focus Etherium.</desc>
        <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="itemOre@6">
        <name>Sunstone</name>
        <desc>Sunstone is only found in the most intently hot locations in all of Minecraft and worlds beyond.  Requiring such intense heat to form, but very low pressure, it is commonly found in the lava lakes of the nether, but can exist in the lava pools of the overworld as well, if you are lucky.</desc>
        <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="itemOre@7">
        <name>Moonstone</name>
        <desc>If one were to look up at the sky at the right time of night, one may see a meteor descending from the sky.  These meteors contain the rare mineral Moonstone.  Where exactly these meteors came from, nobody knows, but the magical properties of Moonstone far excel anything else found in the world.  Studies have shown that the meteors fall more and more often as the moon waxes full, then decreases again as it wanes back to new.</desc>
        <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <relatedEntries>calefactor</relatedEntries>
    </item>
    <item id="essence">
      <name>Essences / Essence Bag</name>
      <desc>Essences are used both in crafting magical items, as well as reagents for spells.  Elemental essences are dropped by their respective guardians, and all essences can also be crafted using the #5Essence Refiner#0.</desc>
      <subitem id="essence@0">
        <name>Arcane Essence</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>essence_bag,essence_refiner</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="essence@1">
        <name>Earth Essence</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>essence_bag,essence_refiner</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="essence@2">
        <name>Air Essence</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>essence_bag,essence_refiner</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="essence@3">
        <name>Fire Essence</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>essence_bag,essence_refiner</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="essence@4">
        <name>Water Essence</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>essence_bag,essence_refiner</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="essence@5">
        <name>Nature Essence</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>essence_bag,essence_refiner</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="essence@6">
        <name>Ice Essence</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>essence_bag,essence_refiner</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="essence@7">
        <name>Lightning Essence</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>essence_bag,essence_refiner</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="essence@8">
        <name>Life Essence</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>essence_bag,essence_refiner</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="essence@9">
        <name>Ender Essence</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>essence_bag,essence_refiner</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="essence@10">
        <name>Pure Essence</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>essence_bag,essence_refiner</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="essence@11">
        <name>High Essence Core</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>essence_bag,essence_refiner</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="essence@12">
        <name>Base Essence Core</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>essence_bag,essence_refiner</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="essence@13">
        <name>Etherium</name>
        <desc>This represents etherium, AM2's power, and will be shown as part of certain spell recipes.  When this appears, ensure your crafting altar is connected to the right kind of Etherium type (check the book on the Lectern, and by color), and flip the lever on the crafting altar.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>altarOfCreation</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="essence_bag">
        <name>Essence Bag</name>
        <desc>The essence bag can be crafted to allow additional storage when adventuring.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>essence_refiner</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </item>
    <item id="runes">
      <name>Runes</name>
      <desc>Runes are the building blocks for spells.  When combined with multiple other items in the right combination, a magical spell scroll can be created.</desc>
      <subitem id="runes@0" unlocked="true">
        <name>Black Rune</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>runebag,keystone</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="runes@1" unlocked="true">
        <name>Blank Rune</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>runebag,keystone</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="runes@2" unlocked="true">
        <name>Blue Rune</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>runebag,keystone</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="runes@3" unlocked="true">
        <name>Brown Rune</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>runebag,keystone</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="runes@4" unlocked="true">
        <name>Cyan Rune</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>runebag,keystone</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="runes@5" unlocked="true">
        <name>Gray Rune</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>runebag,keystone</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="runes@6" unlocked="true">
        <name>Green Rune</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>runebag,keystone</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="runes@7" unlocked="true">
        <name>Light Blue Rune</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>runebag,keystone</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="runes@8" unlocked="true">
        <name>Light Gray Rune</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>runebag,keystone</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="runes@9" unlocked="true">
        <name>Lime Rune</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>runebag,keystone</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="runes@10" unlocked="true">
        <name>Magenta Rune</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>runebag,keystone</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="runes@11" unlocked="true">
        <name>Orange Rune</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>runebag,keystone</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="runes@12" unlocked="true">
        <name>Pink Rune</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>runebag,keystone</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="runes@13" unlocked="true">
        <name>Purple Rune</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>runebag,keystone</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="runes@14" unlocked="true">
        <name>Red Rune</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>runebag,keystone</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="runes@15" unlocked="true">
        <name>White Rune</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>runebag,keystone</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="runes@16" unlocked="true">
        <name>Yellow Rune</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>runebag,keystone</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="runebag" unlocked="true">
        <name>Rune Bag</name>
        <desc>The Rune Bag can hold a few runes, helping to save inventory space.  If you have runes in a rune bag, Keystones will be able to interact with the runes inside it to switch their currently selected combination.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>keystone</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <relatedEntries>keystone</relatedEntries>
    </item>
    <item id="armorMage">
      <name>Mage Armor</name>
      <desc>A more advanced version of simple robes, mage armor allows for slightly more durability, recharge, and protection.  Mage armor, due to the runes inlaid in it, has very high capability to be enchanted.  It also can repair its condition using mana drawn from its wearer.  When wearing a full suit of mage armor, your mana regen speed is increased and all spells are slightly more effective.</desc>
      <subitem id="helmet_mage">
        <name>Mage Hood</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>infusion,armor_xp_infusion</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="chest_mage">
        <name>Mage Robes</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>infusion,armor_xp_infusion</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="legs_mage">
        <name>Mage Leggings</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>infusion,armor_xp_infusion</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="boots_mage">
        <name>Mage Boots</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>infusion,armor_xp_infusion</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <relatedEntries>infusion,armor_xp_infusion</relatedEntries>
    </item>
    <item id="armorBattlemage">
      <name>Battlemage Armor</name>
      <desc>Granted only to mages who have proven themselves true masters, Battlemage Armor offers a good amount of protection.  It has higher durability than Mage Armor, but has a slower repair rate and less enchantability, as well as giving lesser versions of the magical bonuses that mage armor does.  Battlemage Armor can also be given XP which will unlock protective spells that will come to the aid of its wearer, draining some of the magic within the armor.  The magic will then infuse back over time from your own mana pool.</desc>
      <subitem id="helmet_battlemage">
        <name>Battlemage Circlet</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>infusion,armor_xp_infusion</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="chest_battlemage">
        <name>Battlemage Armor</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>infusion,armor_xp_infusion</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="legs_battlemage">
        <name>Battlemage Leggings</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>infusion,armor_xp_infusion</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="boots_battlemage">
        <name>Battlemage Boots</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>infusion,armor_xp_infusion</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <relatedEntries>infusion</relatedEntries>
    </item>
    <item id="affinityTomes">
      <name>Affinity Tomes</name>
      <desc>Affinity tomes contain detailed reports and information gather by magi over the years pertaining to a specific affinitiy.  With the exception of the General affinity tome, they will, when read, give you a 10% boost to that specific affinity, while simultaneously reducing your progress in all other affinities by 10%.</desc>
      <subitem id="affinity_tome@0">
        <name>Affinity Tome: General</name>
        <desc>The general affinity tome is special in that it can unlock a locked affinity state.  It will reduce all affinity progression by 10% without boosting any of them.</desc>
        <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="affinity_tome@1">
        <name>Affinity Tome: Arcane</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="affinity_tome@2">
        <name>Affinity Tome: Water</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="affinity_tome@3">
        <name>Affinity Tome: Fire</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="affinity_tome@4">
        <name>Affinity Tome: Earth</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="affinity_tome@5">
        <name>Affinity Tome: Air</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="affinity_tome@6">
        <name>Affinity Tome: Lightning</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="affinity_tome@7">
        <name>Affinity Tome: Ice</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="affinity_tome@8">
        <name>Affinity Tome: Nature</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="affinity_tome@9">
        <name>Affinity Tome: Life</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="affinity_tome@10">
        <name>Affinity Tome: Ender</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </item>
    <item id="foci">
      <name>Foci</name>
      <desc>Foci are used inside specific Ars Magica machines to change the way they function.</desc>
      <subitem id="chargefocus">
        <name>Charge Focus</name>
        <desc>
					Charge Foci are used to increase the rate at which Ars Magica machines charge.  In #9Calefactors#0 and #9Arcane Reconstructors#0, they also increase the rate at which the machine performs its task.
				</desc>
        <relatedEntries>summoner,arcanereconstructor,arcane_deconstructor</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="manafocus">
        <name>Mana Focus</name>
        <desc>
					Mana Foci are used to decrease costs of operation in Ars Magica machines.
				</desc>
        <relatedEntries>summoner,calefactor</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="lesserfocus">
        <name>Lesser Focus</name>
        <desc>
					Lesser Foci are used in various AM2 machines, and instruct them to operate in different ways.
				</desc>
        <relatedEntries>blockseerstone</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="standardfocus">
        <name>Standard Focus</name>
        <desc>
					Standard Foci are used in various AM2 machines, and instruct them to operate in different ways.
				</desc>
        <relatedEntries>blockseerstone</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="greaterfocus">
        <name>Greater Focus</name>
        <desc>
					Greater Foci are used in various AM2 machines, and instruct them to operate in different ways.
				</desc>
        <relatedEntries>blockseerstone</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="item_focus">
        <name>Item Focus</name>
        <desc>
					Item foci are used in the #9Seer Stone#0, and instruct it to search for nearby items on the ground.
				</desc>
        <relatedEntries>blockseerstone</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="player_focus">
        <name>Player Focus</name>
        <desc>
					Player foci are used in the #9Seer Stone#0, and instruct it to search for nearby players.
				</desc>
        <relatedEntries>blockseerstone</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="monster_focus">
        <name>Monster Focus</name>
        <desc>
					Monster foci are used in the #9Seer Stone#0, and instruct it to search for nearby mobs (Zombies, Skeletons, etc).
				</desc>
        <relatedEntries>blockseerstone</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="creature_focus">
        <name>Creature Focus</name>
        <desc>
					Creature foci are used in the #9Seer Stone#0, and instruct it to search for nearby critters (Sheep, Cows, etc).
				</desc>
        <relatedEntries>blockseerstone</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <relatedEntries>flicker_lure</relatedEntries>
    </item>
    <item id="keystone">
      <name>Keystone</name>
      <desc>Keystones are used to link Gateways to each other, as well as to restrict access to Ars Magica machines.  The UI for these blocks will not open if you are not holding a keystone with the same rune combination.</desc>
      <relatedEntries>keystonechest,blockkeystonerecepticle,blockastralbarrier,blockseerstone,keystoneDoors,gateways</relatedEntries>
    </item>
    <item id="mana_cake">
      <name>Mana Cake</name>
      <desc>Mana Cakes both restore hunger and give a boost to mana regeneration.  Plus, it's cake!</desc>
      <relatedEntries>mana_potion</relatedEntries>
    </item>
    <item id="mana_potion">
      <name>Mana Potions</name>
      <desc>Mana potions restore mana instantly when imbibed.  You get an empty bottle back after drinking one.  Mana potions can be bundled by combining 3 of the same type of potion with string.  The bundle can be used 3 times and will also return the empty bottles.  The final potion drank will also return the string.</desc>
      <subitem id="mana_potion_lesser">
        <name>Lesser Mana Potion</name>
        <desc>The lesser mana potion is the magical equivalent to a cup of coffee:  a short boost, but it won't get you through an entire day.  One use will restore 100 mana.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>mana_cake</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="mana_potion_standard">
        <name>Standard Mana Potion</name>
        <desc>The standard mana potion gives a decently upgraded amount of mana from the lesser one for not much of a material cost.  One use will restore 250 mana.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>mana_cake</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="mana_potion_greater">
        <name>Greater Mana Potion</name>
        <desc>The greater mana potion uses the power of #5vinteum#0 combined with a #9Awkward Potion#0 at a brewing stand to restore a good amount of mana.  One use will restore 2000 mana.  The crafting table recipe is temporary while I figure out the derpy brewing stand.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>mana_cake</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="mana_potion_epic">
        <name>Epic Mana Potion</name>
        <desc>The epic mana potion is created by combining #5arcane ash#0 with a #9Awkward Potion#0 at a brewing stand to restore 5000 mana per potion.  The crafting table recipe is temporary while I figure out the derpy brewing stand.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>mana_cake</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="mana_potion_legendary">
        <name>Legendary Mana Potion</name>
        <desc>The legendary mana potion is created by combining #5purified vinteum dust#0 with a #9Awkward Potion#0 at a brewing stand.  One potion will restore a whopping 10000 mana!  The crafting table recipe is temporary while I figure out the derpy brewing stand.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>mana_cake</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="mana_boost_potion">
        <name>Infused Etherium Potion</name>
        <desc>By taking a #5bucket of Liquid Etherium#0, a mage can combine it with #5chimerite#0 and #5tarma root#0 in order to create a potion to give a temporary boost to maximum mana.  Unfortunately, the process is minimally efficient and much of the Liquid Etherium is lost along the way.</desc>
        <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
	  <subitem id="mana_martini">
        <name>Mana Martini</name>
        <desc>In honour of Mithion's final release of AM2, which happens to be #9version 007#0, you can now make a Mana Martini that, when drank, will give you a 25% reduction in burnout gained from casting spells.</desc>
        <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </item>
    <item id="crystal_wrench">
      <name>Crystal Wrench</name>
      <desc>
	  The crystal wrench serves many purposes.  It can be used to direct Etherium through your power network.  
	  To do this, #9right click first on the source of Etherium you want to use#0.  This marks the source block. Then, #9right click on the destination while still holding the wrench#0.  
	  #5Note that there is no need to click on Etherium Conduits along the way - just click on the final block.  The power system will attempt to pathfind through nearby Etherium Conduits automatically#0.  
	  If that fails for any reason, you will be notified.  This will force a pairing, and ensures the Etherium goes where you want it to.  
	  !d 
	  If you #9sneak while right clicking on the source#0, the wrench's crystal will turn green.  This means the crystal wrench is remembering the source block's location, and you can click on several destinations 
	  in a row without having to return to the source.  Each destination right clicked on in this state will be paired (if possible) to the remembered source.  
	  !d
	  You can also disconnect power nodes by #9Sneaking and right clicking#0 on a #5non-powered block#0.  This will switch the wrench's mode from link to unlink.  You can see the change when the crystal on the wrench 
	  turns red.  To switch it back, simply repeat the sneak right click to change the crystal back to purple.  If you have a stored location, it will need to be cleared first before the mode can be switched (which is 
	  also done by sneak right-clicking a non-powered block).
	  !p 
	  The crystal wrench can also be used to show hidden particle emitters, and can copy their settings by right clicking.  The settings can then be pasted to another emitter by right clicking.  
	  Each time you "paste" settings, you will need to copy them again if you wish to paste to additional emitters.</desc>
      <relatedEntries>obelisk,mana_battery</relatedEntries>
    </item>
    <item id="spell_parchment">
      <name>Spell Parchment</name>
      <desc>Any mage that wants to cast spells without the need of some sort of staff or wand needs something to write the spell down on.  This has worked for thousands of years, and surprisingly nothing more effective has been invented yet.</desc>
      <relatedEntries>altarOfCreation,inscriptionTable</relatedEntries>
    </item>
    <item id="crystal_phylactery">
      <name>Crystal Phylactery</name>
      <desc>The crystal phylactery is a life-force capturing device.  A magic user who has one of these in her inventory can trap small pieces of souls from slain foes.  Once the phylactery is full, she can use it as a component for a spell to summon that very creature to do her bidding.</desc>
      <relatedEntries>Summon</relatedEntries>
    </item>
    <item id="spell_staff_magitech">
      <name>Magitech's Staff</name>
      <desc>The magitech's staff is a modified version of a spell staff that is attuned to ambient mana.  It can be used to sense the Etherium levels in powered blocks by right clicking the block with the staff in your hand.  It gains additional functionality if you have the #9Magitech's Goggles#0 equipped.  
			!d
			The Magitech's Staff can also be used to reclaim a #9Magic Broom#0.  Simply right click the broom with the staff in your hand to reclaim it.</desc>
      <relatedEntries>magitechGoggles,magic_broom</relatedEntries>
    </item>
    <item id="spell_book">
      <name>Spell Book</name>
      <desc>The spell book is a useful item to have, allowing mages to organize their spells and save space at the same time.  The spell book, when equipped, can be scrolled through either by pressing x/z (default), or by sneaking and rolling the mouse wheel.  Spell books can be dyed a variety of different colors.  They can also be #5enchanted#0 with some useful powers.</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </item>
    <item id="magic_broom">
      <name>Magic Broom</name>
      <desc>You have taken the magical properties of Arcane Ash and combined them with a broom.  Why?  You're not entirely sure.  What you do know is that this broom loves to keep the area clean, picking up any loose items near it and putting them in it's assigned chest.  To place the broom once you craft it, right click on a #5any block with an inventory#0 with the broom equipped.  It won't work otherwise. Currently the broom will grab all loose items, though it will be configurable at a later time.
			!d
			The broom can be reclaimed by right clicking it with a #9Magitech's Staff#0 in your hand.</desc>
      <relatedEntries>spell_staff_magitech</relatedEntries>
    </item>
    <item id="nature_scythe">
      <name>Nature's Scythe</name>
      <desc>Taken from the guardian of nature itself, this scythe wields immense power.  It can clear leaves and plants with astounding efficiency.  It can be thrown like a boomerang by right clicking, though it costs 250 mana to do so.  All plant clearing effects apply while thrown, and damage is increased.</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </item>
    <item id="arcane_spellbook">
      <name>Arcane Spellbook</name>
      <desc>Imbued with unknowable enchantments by ancient mages, the arcane spell book #9increases the effectiveness of all spells cast from it#0.  Damage is increased, and mana cost is lowered.  Things like duration and radius are not modified.</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </item>
    <item id="winter_arm">
      <name>Winter's Grasp</name>
      <desc>Taken from the guardian of winter, this arm can be used as a blunt weapon.  It retains its unearthly chill, and drastically slows and weakens all struck with it.  For 250 mana, it can be thrown, and will pull back an entity to you if it is hit by the arm, applying a more powerful slow and weaken effect.</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </item>
    <item id="air_sled">
      <name>Air Sled</name>
      <desc>The air sled allows you to take to the sky with ease.  It is slightly faster than creative mode flight, but does not afford the same level of control.</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </item>
    <item id="earth_armor">
      <name>Earth Armor</name>
      <desc>The earth armor is the chest of the guardian of earth.  It offers significant physical damage resistance for a single piece of armor.  It adds a sizeable amount of damage (+4) and knockback to unarmed strikes (no item equipped).</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </item>
    <item id="water_orbs">
      <name>Water Orbs</name>
      <desc>The water orbs allow you to control water subconsciously.  While wearing them (they are a leg slot item), you will not be pushed by flowing liquids.  You will also have infinite breath while underwater.</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </item>
    <item id="fire_ears">
      <name>Fire Antenna</name>
      <desc>The fire antenna, when worn, grant full immunity to fire and lava.</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </item>
    <item id="workbenchUpgrade">
      <name>Workbench Grid Upgrade</name>
      <desc>You've figured out a way to make an upgrade for the Magician's workbench that makes the secondary grid a 3x3 instead of a 2x2.  Simply craft it and right click a placed bench to apply it.  Keep in mind, the modifications are rather fragile, and will break off if the workbench is destroyed and will have to be re-made.</desc>
      <relatedEntries>magiciansWorkbench</relatedEntries>
    </item>
    <item id="bindingcatalysts">
      <name>Binding Catalyst</name>
      <desc>Binding Catalysts are used by the #5Binding#0 shape to determine what type of tool or weapon will be bound.</desc>
      <subitem id="bindingCatalyst@0">
        <name>Binding Catalyst: Pickaxe</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>Binding</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="bindingCatalyst@1">
        <name>Binding Catalyst: Axe</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>Binding</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="bindingCatalyst@2">
        <name>Binding Catalyst: Sword</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>Binding</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="bindingCatalyst@3">
        <name>Binding Catalyst: Shovel</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>Binding</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="bindingCatalyst@4">
        <name>Binding Catalyst: Hoe</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>Binding</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="bindingCatalyst@5">
        <name>Binding Catalyst: Bow</name>
        <desc>This one isn't implemented yet - look for it soon!</desc>
        <relatedEntries>Binding</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </item>
    <item id="warding_candle">
      <name>Warding Candle</name>
      <desc>Warding Candles, when held, are moving sources of light.  They can also be #9attuned#0 to a specific block by #9sneaking and right clicking on the block while holding the candle#0.  This will cause the candle flame to turn blue when within 15 blocks of the specified block, and red when within 5 blocks.  A warding candle will burn for 15 minutes, but is put out when not equipped.
			!d
			Warding candles are also used in #5Rituals#0, and are placed down as part of the layout.  A Warding Candle that has been attuned cannot be used in a ritual.</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </item>
    <item id="flicker_jar">
      <name>Flicker Jar</name>
      <desc>Flicker Jars are used to catch flickers.  Simply right click on the flicker and you will trap it inside the jar.  Sounds simple, right?  Have fun...</desc>
      <relatedEntries>Flicker</relatedEntries>
    </item>
    <item id="enderBoots">
      <name>Ender Boots</name>
      <desc>The Ender Boots are a rare drop from the #5Ender Guardian#0.  When wearing these boots, #9sneaking and jumping will reverse gravity#0!  This will only apply to you, and you will fall upwards.  Normal falling damage applies.  You cannot reverse gravity while airborne.</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </item>
    <item id="lightningcharm">
      <name>Lightning Charm</name>
      <desc>The Lightning Charm is a rare drop from the #5Lightning Guardian#0.  Sneaking and right clicking will toggle the item on and off.  When on, its static electricity draws in nearby items automatically.</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </item>
    <item id="lifeward">
      <name>Life Ward</name>
      <desc>The Life Ward is a rare drop from the #5Life Guardian#0.  When in your action bar, you will slowly generate a shield around you that will absorb incoming damage.  It will generate up to 20 additional temporary hit points.  The hit points remain if the Ward is removed from your inventory, but will not replenish themselves without it.</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </item>
    <item id="magitechGoggles">
      <name>Magitech's Goggles</name>
      <desc>The Magitech's Goggles are a companion piece to the #9Magitech's Staff#0.  When worn, you can sneak and right click powered blocks with a Magitech's Staff.  You will then be able to see all of the incoming power types to the selected machine, and where they come from.  The goggles will also allow you to see broken power links; where a power path was before, but something went wrong (for example, a conduit was broken).  Broken power link blocks cannot be broken by hand, but they can be replaced by any block.</desc>
      <relatedEntries>spell_staff_magitech,brokenLink</relatedEntries>
    </item>
    <item id="flickerFocus">
      <name>Flicker Focus</name>
      <desc>Flicker foci are used to create livable conditions inside a #9Flicker Habitat#0 for Flickers.  It will enable them to perform several tasks, each of which are detailed to the right.</desc>
      <relatedEntries>flickerHabitat,Flicker,crystalMarker</relatedEntries>
      <subitem id="flickerFocus@1">
        <name>Flicker Focus: Item Transport</name>
        <desc>The air flickers contained within this crystal have been attuned to the movement of items. Placing this within a #9Flicker Habitat#0 will allow you to link it with #9Crystal Markers#0 to interact with inventories containing items. To link the habitat containing this foci with a #9Crystal Marker#0 simply right click on the #9Flicker Habitat#0 then right click on the #9Crystal Marker#0. This foci can be upgraded using additional #9Flicker Habitats#0 with flickers inside them. This foci can operate without access to Etherium however it is very slow. Adding power increases the speed and allows the foci to make use of attached upgrades. !d Arcane: !l Increases the number of items the flickers inside can move at one time. The first arcane flicker will increase the count to 32, each additional arcane flicker will add an additional 32 items to the air flickers carrying capacity !d Lightning: !l Lightning flickers will increase the speed at which the flickers move items. Additional lightning flickers after the first will still increase the speed but suffer from diminishing returns. Most Magitechs belive its a waste to go higher then three lightning flickers.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>flickerFocus,crystalMarker</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="flickerFocus@3">
        <name>Flicker Focus: Interdiction</name>
        <desc>Arcane and air flickers working together can create a wall around their habitat if they are provided enough Etherium to do so. By placing this focus in a #9Flicker Habitat#0 and providing it with Etherium a nearly invisible wall is created in a 6 block radius from the #9Flicker Habitat#0.  Modifying this with an #9Ender Flicker Jar#0 will also cause the #9Containment#0 effect to apply. !d Placing #9Ice Flicker Upgrades#0 to this focus will increase the radius of the containment field by one per ice flicker added.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>flickerFocus</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="flickerFocus@9">
        <name>Flicker Focus: Containment</name>
        <desc>Ender and air flickers working in tandem can create a wall surrounding their #9Flicker Habitat#0 provided they have been given the Etherium to do so. Placing this focus in a habitat and providing it with Etherium will create a nearly invisible wall in a 6 block radius from their #9Flicker Habitat#0 that non-player entities can not pass out of.  Modifying this with an #9Arcane Flicker Jar#0 will also cause the #9Interdiction#0 effect to apply. !d Placing #9Ice Flicker Upgrades#0 to this focus will increase the radius of the containment field by one per ice flicker added.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>flickerFocus</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="flickerFocus@4">
        <name>Flicker Focus: Packed Earth</name>
        <desc>Earth flickers when contained within this focus can flatten terrain in a 6 block radius around their #9Flicker Habitat#0 using materials stored in an inventory below their habitat. While these flickers can operate without access to Etherium they are much faster when they have access to a source of power.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>flickerFocus</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="flickerFocus@36">
        <name>Flicker Focus: Flat Lands</name>
        <desc>The earth and ice flickers inside this focus will flatten a 6 block radius area surrounding their #9Flicker Habitat#0. They can operate without power but are much more effective when connected to a source of Etherium.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>flickerFocus</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="flickerFocus@64">
        <name>Flicker Focus: Progeny</name>
        <desc>The life flickers inside this focus can use a source of Etherium to cause animals within 8 blocks to breed.  This focus requires etherium of any kind for each operation.  The default operation time is 2000 ticks (100 seconds), but this can be reduced by placing additional habitats adjacent to the original and placing lightning flicker jars in them.  There isn't much point in adding more than 4, as the minimum is 600 ticks (30 seconds).  Each upgrade multiplies the current duration by 0.75, so the effect is diminishing.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>flickerFocus</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="flickerFocus@80">
        <name>Flicker Focus: Butchery</name>
        <desc>The flickers inside this focus are constantly at odds. The fire flicker seeks to consume the life around its self, while the life flicker seeks to defend it. The balance that is struck in this conflict is that all but two of every animal type with a 6 block radius around the #9Flicker Habitat#0 that contains this focus will eventually be killed. Provided that the fire flicker has access to a source of Etherium to do its grisly work.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>flickerFocus</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="flickerFocus@134">
        <name>Flicker Focus: Lunar Tides</name>
        <desc>The three flickers inside this focus can use their combined power to pull moonstone meteors that would land within 128 blocks of their #9Flicker Habitat#0 to land within 8 blocks. However to accomplish this they need a trickle of Etherium to keep them alert and watching for meteors.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>flickerFocus</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="flickerFocus@144">
        <name>Flicker Focus: Light</name>
        <desc>The fire and lightning flickers contained within can use the power of the sun stone used in the construction of their focus to light a 16 block radius around their #9Flicker Habitat#0.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>flickerFocus</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="flickerFocus@384">
        <name>Flicker Focus: Felled Oak</name>
        <desc>The nature flicker contained within this focus will seek out trees within a 6 block radius around their #9Flicker Habitat#0, once they do the lightning flickers will fell the tree one block at a time. These flickers can operate without a source of power but they are much faster when they have a source of Etherium to fuel themselves. !d Lightning flickers can be used as augments to make the process faster as well. !d If a nature flicker augment is added, the flickers will also re-plant saplings from an adjacent chest.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>flickerFocus</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="flickerFocus@512">
        <name>Flicker Focus: Gentle Rains</name>
        <desc>The water flicker contained within this focus will hydrate the terrain in a 6 block radius around it's #9Flicker Habitat#0.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>flickerFocus</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="flickerFocus@832">
        <name>Flicker Focus: Nature's Bounty</name>
        <desc>The life, nature and water flickers contained within this focus will work together to help all plants within a 6 block radius grow faster. These hard working flickers will help all nearby plants with or without Etherium but providing them with a source of power will allow them to do their work faster.  When powered, modifying this habitat with a #9Water Flicker Jar#0 will also cause the #9Gentle Rains#0 effect to apply.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>flickerFocus</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
	  <subitem id="flickerFocus@768">
        <name>Flicker Focus: Fishing</name>
        <desc>The combination of Water and Nature flickers causes them to be able to find creatures that live in water.  It does require power to maintain the search, however, as the flickers cover a great distance in a short time.  If augmented with adjacent habitats containing lightning flickers, they are able to move even faster, causing them to naturally find fish more often.  Doing so will increase the overall power use. !d The focus requires a 3x3 square of water below it that is also at least 2 blocks deep in order to function.  It will output fish into an adjacent inventory if possible, or drop them as an item if no inventory is present. !d A redstone signal must be provided for the flickers to start working.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>flickerFocus</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
    </item>
    <item id="wizardChalk">
      <name>Wizard's Chalk</name>
      <desc>Wizard's Chalk is used to create #9Rituals#0 by drawing the correct shapes on the ground.</desc>
      <relatedEntries>corruption,purification,hourglass</relatedEntries>
    </item>
    <item id="playerjournal">
      <name>Journal</name>
      <desc>Journals can be used to #9record your experiences#0 for later use.  These experiences can #9later be recovered by reading the journal#0.</desc>
      <relatedEntries />
    </item>
	<item id="deficit_crystal">
      <name>Deficit Crystal</name>
      <desc>Often noted as the antimatter of magic, Deficit represents a void in the fabric of reality.  You've managed to create a refined, crystallized version of it.  Crystals like these are often used in the unmaking of things.</desc>
      <relatedEntries>essence_refiner,arcane_deconstructor</relatedEntries>
    </item>
    <item id="inscriptionUpgrades">
		<name>Inscription Table Upgrades</name>
		<desc>These upgrades improve the functionality of your #9Inscription Table#0, allowing you to make use of more shape groups.</desc>
		<subitem id="inscription_upgrade@0">
			<name>Tier 1 Upgrade</name>
			<desc></desc>
			<relatedEntries>inscriptionTable</relatedEntries>
		</subitem>
		<subitem id="inscription_upgrade@1">
			<name>Tier 2 Upgrade</name>
			<desc></desc>
			<relatedEntries>inscriptionTable</relatedEntries>
		</subitem>
		<subitem id="inscription_upgrade@2">
			<name>Tier 3 Upgrade</name>
			<desc></desc>
			<relatedEntries>inscriptionTable</relatedEntries>
		</subitem>
		<relatedEntries>inscriptionTable</relatedEntries>
	</item>
  </items>
  <structures>
    <structure id="obelisk_structure">
      <name>Obelisk</name>
      <controller>TileEntityObelisk</controller>
      <desc>The Obelisk is somewhat of a magical furnace.  It can generate Etherium by burning #5Vinteum Dust#0 or #5Liquid Etherium#0 out of a bucket.  The Obelisk generates #5Neutral Etherium#0.
			!d
			The structure depicted here does not have to be built all at once; it can be built in sections.  The #9Wizard's Chalk Circle#0 is a standalone upgrade that when completed, will increase the output of the Obelisk's burn capabilities.  The #9Pillars#0 are another upgrade, and will further increase the output of the Obelisk.  
			!d
			If space is a concern however, these upgrades are not required for the Obelisk to function.</desc>
      <relatedEntries>obelisk,crystal_wrench,spell_staff_magitech,magitechGoggles,rituals_overview</relatedEntries>
    </structure>
    <structure id="blackaurem_structure">
      <name>Black Aurem</name>
      <controller>TileEntityBlackAurem</controller>
      <desc>A sinister construction, the Black Aurem slowly but invariably pulls living creatures from around it inward to its center.  Upon reaching the middle, bolts of pure darkness lash out and tear the life force out of the creature. The Black Aurem generates #4Dark Etherium#0.  Mobs killed by the Aurem drop neither XP nor loot.
			!d
			The Black Aurem is created by performing the #9Ritual of Corruption#0 on an #9Obelisk#0.  Like the Obelisk, the Black Aurem can be upgraded by adding certain multiblock configurations around it.  The first of these is the #5Wizard's Chalk Circle#0, and will increase the amount of power generated from each mob the Aurem consumes.  The second upgrade is the #5Pillars#0, which will further increase the power generation.  The pillars can also have specific #5cap upgrades#0, which modify the amount of benefit.
			!d
			Obsidian and Chimerite are on the same level, with Sunstone giving a large bonus to generation.
			!d
			Neither the chalk circle or the pillars are required for the Aurem to function.</desc>
      <relatedEntries>obelisk,corruption,crystal_wrench,spell_staff_magitech</relatedEntries>
    </structure>
    <structure id="celestialprism_structure">
      <name>Celestial Prism</name>
      <controller>TileEntityCelestialPrism</controller>
      <desc>The Celestial Prism is a purified form of the Obelisk that generates #9Light Etherium#0.  It generates this power slowly, but passively.  It requires nothing more than daylight to generate its power.  You will know it is generating when runes of power begin to swirl around the crystal.
			!d
			To create the Celestial Prism, perform the #9Ritual of Purification#0 on an #9Obelisk#0.  Like the Obelisk, the Celestial Prism can be upgraded by adding certain multiblock configurations around it.  The first of these is the #5Wizard's Chalk Circle#0, and will increase the amount of power generated by the prism.  The second upgrade is the #5Pillars#0, which will further increase the rate at which power is generated.  The pillars can also have specific #5cap upgrades#0, which modify the amount of benefit.  
			!d
			The most noticable effect are the #9Moonstone Caps#0, which increase the power by a significant amount, but also switches the prism to charge at night instead of during the day.</desc>
      <relatedEntries>obelisk,rituals_overview,crystal_wrench,spell_staff_magitech</relatedEntries>
    </structure>
    <structure id="gateways">
      <name>Gateway</name>
      <controller>TileEntityKeystoneRecepticle</controller>
      <desc>Gateways are quite efficient at short range, but longer distances require significantly more Etherium.  The maximum range for a Gateway has been tested to be roughly 12km, though an extreme amount of Etherium is required to traverse such a span.  A keystone can be inserted into the Keystone Receptacle in order to lock the gateway to the keystone's rune combination.  Only then by activating another gateway with a matching keystone can one arrive at the keyed gateway.  If the key does not match or no keystone is held at all when the gate is activated, it will be as if the keyed gateway doesn't even exist.  This method can be used to control where you will wind up in the gateway network.</desc>
      <relatedEntries>rituals_overview</relatedEntries>
    </structure>
    <structure id="craftingAltar">
      <name>Crafting Altar</name>
      <controller>TileEntityCraftingAltar</controller>
      <desc>
			Harnessing the forces of creation, the crafting altar allows mages to work miracles of magic.  This is where you will create all of your spells in Ars Magica.  The structure is upgradeable by 2 main groups, the caps and the main material.  Both groups individually increase the available power of the altar and allow it to make more powerful spells.  The main blocks, in order of power, are as follows:
			!l
			Wood Planks (+1 Effect)
			!l
			Stone Brick (+1 Effect)
			!l
			Sandstone (+1 Effect)
			!l
			Bricks (+2 Effects)
			!l
			Witchwood (+2 Effects)
			!l
			Nether Bricks (+3 Effects)
			!l
			Nether Quartz (+3 Effects)
			!l
			!l
			For the caps (grand total of 5 in the structure), the progression is as follows:
			!l
			Glass (+1 Effect)
			!l
			Coal Blocks (+2 Effects)
			!l
			Redstone Blocks (+3 Effects)
			!l
			Iron Blocks (+4 Effects)
			!l
			Lapis Blocks (+5 Effects)
			!l
			Gold Blocks (+6 Effects)
			!l
			Diamond Blocks (+7 Effects)
			!l
			Emerald Blocks (+8 Effects)
			!l
			Moonstone Blocks (+9 Effects)
			!l
			Sunstone Blocks (+10 Effects)
			!l
			!l
			These stack cumulatively, so for example wood planks with glass caps would equal a maximum of 2 effects, whereas stone bricks with redstone caps would have a maximum of 4 effects in a spell.  The maximum number of effects you can currently have on a spell is 13.
			</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </structure>
    <structure id="inlays_structure">
      <name>Inlay Rings</name>
      <desc>Inlay Rings are created by putting inlay blocks into a 3x3 ring with an empty center block.  All blocks must be on the same Y level, and must all be of the same type of inlay block.  You will know it is working when runes begin to appear on the blocks.</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </structure>
    <ritual id="rituals_overview">
      <name>Rituals</name>
      <desc>Rituals are created using Wizard's Chalk and Warding Candles.  Arranging them in the correct pattern can enable you to do some truly powerful magic.  !d Rituals will usually require additional items to be thrown on the ground in order for the ritual to succeed.  These items can be thrown anywhere on the ground inside the radius of the Wizard's Chalk.  !d Once you have your ritual laid out, and your items thrown in, you will need to cast the proper spell in order to kick everything off.  The reagents will depend on the spell being cast,and order does matter.  For example, when throwing down runes to recall to a gateway using a ritual, the order of the runes will become the keystone combination. !d  The spell must target the exact center block of the ritual, on the same y-level as the chalk and candles.  This is usually a block placed in the center, or an entity standing in the middle.  !d  If it doesn't work, make sure you are in the middle of the chalk, that the layout is correct, and that you have the correct reagents for the correct ritual!</desc>
      <relatedEntries>wizardChalk,warding_candle</relatedEntries>
      <subitem id="purification">
        <name>Ritual of Purification</name>
        <desc>The ritual of Purification is used to purify an obelisk into a celestial prism.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>obelisk,wizardChalk,warding_candle</relatedEntries>
        <ritualName>purification</ritualName>
        <ritualController>Light</ritualController>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="corruption_prism">
        <name>Ritual of Corruption (Obelisk)</name>
        <desc>The Ritual of Corruption is used to corrupt an Obelisk into a Black Aurem.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>obelisk,wizardChalk,warding_candle</relatedEntries>
        <ritualName>corruption</ritualName>
        <ritualController>FireDamage</ritualController>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="corruption_obelisk">
        <name>Ritual of Corruption (Monster Spawner)</name>
        <desc>The Ritual of Corruption can be used to pick up a Monster Spawner to be used later.  The ritual removes the spawning capabilities of the spawner, so they will need to be re-added to it somehow.  Rift or Life Tap can be used as well, so each tree specialization can perform this.  The reagents are the same for all three spell options.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>Rift,LifeTap,wizardChalk,warding_candle</relatedEntries>
        <ritualName>corruption</ritualName>
        <ritualController>AstralDistortion</ritualController>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="extend_blind">
        <name>Hourglass Ritual (Blind)</name>
        <desc>The hourglass ritual can be used to extend a buff to a significantly longer duration.  It adds 180 seconds plus an additional 180 seconds for each Buff Power modifier included in the same spell stage as the buff.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>wizardChalk</relatedEntries>
        <ritualName>hourglass</ritualName>
        <ritualController>Blind</ritualController>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="extend_charm">
        <name>Hourglass Ritual (Charm)</name>
        <desc>The hourglass ritual can be used to extend a buff to a significantly longer duration.  It adds 180 seconds plus an additional 180 seconds for each Buff Power modifier included in the same spell stage as the buff.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>wizardChalk</relatedEntries>
        <ritualName>hourglass</ritualName>
        <ritualController>Charm</ritualController>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="extend_entangle">
        <name>Hourglass Ritual (Entangle)</name>
        <desc>The hourglass ritual can be used to extend a buff to a significantly longer duration.  It adds 180 seconds plus an additional 180 seconds for each Buff Power modifier included in the same spell stage as the buff.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>wizardChalk</relatedEntries>
        <ritualName>hourglass</ritualName>
        <ritualController>Entangle</ritualController>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="extend_flight">
        <name>Hourglass Ritual (Flight)</name>
        <desc>The hourglass ritual can be used to extend a buff to a significantly longer duration.  It adds 180 seconds plus an additional 180 seconds for each Buff Power modifier included in the same spell stage as the buff.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>wizardChalk</relatedEntries>
        <ritualName>hourglass</ritualName>
        <ritualController>Flight</ritualController>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="extend_freeze">
        <name>Hourglass Ritual (Freeze)</name>
        <desc>The hourglass ritual can be used to extend a buff to a significantly longer duration.  It adds 180 seconds plus an additional 180 seconds for each Buff Power modifier included in the same spell stage as the buff.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>wizardChalk</relatedEntries>
        <ritualName>hourglass</ritualName>
        <ritualController>Freeze</ritualController>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="extend_fury">
        <name>Hourglass Ritual (Fury)</name>
        <desc>The hourglass ritual can be used to extend a buff to a significantly longer duration.  It adds 180 seconds plus an additional 180 seconds for each Buff Power modifier included in the same spell stage as the buff.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>wizardChalk</relatedEntries>
        <ritualName>hourglass</ritualName>
        <ritualController>Fury</ritualController>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="extend_gravitywell">
        <name>Hourglass Ritual (Gravity Well)</name>
        <desc>The hourglass ritual can be used to extend a buff to a significantly longer duration.  It adds 180 seconds plus an additional 180 seconds for each Buff Power modifier included in the same spell stage as the buff.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>wizardChalk</relatedEntries>
        <ritualName>hourglass</ritualName>
        <ritualController>GravityWell</ritualController>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="extend_haste">
        <name>Hourglass Ritual (Haste)</name>
        <desc>The hourglass ritual can be used to extend a buff to a significantly longer duration.  It adds 180 seconds plus an additional 180 seconds for each Buff Power modifier included in the same spell stage as the buff.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>wizardChalk</relatedEntries>
        <ritualName>hourglass</ritualName>
        <ritualController>Haste</ritualController>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="extend_invisibility">
        <name>Hourglass Ritual (Invisibility)</name>
        <desc>The hourglass ritual can be used to extend a buff to a significantly longer duration.  It adds 180 seconds plus an additional 180 seconds for each Buff Power modifier included in the same spell stage as the buff.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>wizardChalk</relatedEntries>
        <ritualName>hourglass</ritualName>
        <ritualController>Invisibility</ritualController>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="extend_leap">
        <name>Hourglass Ritual (Leap)</name>
        <desc>The hourglass ritual can be used to extend a buff to a significantly longer duration.  It adds 180 seconds plus an additional 180 seconds for each Buff Power modifier included in the same spell stage as the buff.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>wizardChalk</relatedEntries>
        <ritualName>hourglass</ritualName>
        <ritualController>Leap</ritualController>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="extend_levitation">
        <name>Hourglass Ritual (Levitation)</name>
        <desc>The hourglass ritual can be used to extend a buff to a significantly longer duration.  It adds 180 seconds plus an additional 180 seconds for each Buff Power modifier included in the same spell stage as the buff.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>wizardChalk</relatedEntries>
        <ritualName>hourglass</ritualName>
        <ritualController>Levitate</ritualController>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="extend_manashield">
        <name>Hourglass Ritual (Mana Shield)</name>
        <desc>The hourglass ritual can be used to extend a buff to a significantly longer duration.  It adds 180 seconds plus an additional 180 seconds for each Buff Power modifier included in the same spell stage as the buff.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>wizardChalk</relatedEntries>
        <ritualName>hourglass</ritualName>
        <ritualController>ManaShield</ritualController>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="extend_nightvision">
        <name>Hourglass Ritual (Night Vision)</name>
        <desc>The hourglass ritual can be used to extend a buff to a significantly longer duration.  It adds 180 seconds plus an additional 180 seconds for each Buff Power modifier included in the same spell stage as the buff.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>wizardChalk</relatedEntries>
        <ritualName>hourglass</ritualName>
        <ritualController>NightVision</ritualController>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="extend_shield">
        <name>Hourglass Ritual (Shield)</name>
        <desc>The hourglass ritual can be used to extend a buff to a significantly longer duration.  It adds 180 seconds plus an additional 180 seconds for each Buff Power modifier included in the same spell stage as the buff.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>wizardChalk</relatedEntries>
        <ritualName>hourglass</ritualName>
        <ritualController>Shield</ritualController>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="extend_slow">
        <name>Hourglass Ritual (Slow)</name>
        <desc>The hourglass ritual can be used to extend a buff to a significantly longer duration.  It adds 180 seconds plus an additional 180 seconds for each Buff Power modifier included in the same spell stage as the buff.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>wizardChalk</relatedEntries>
        <ritualName>hourglass</ritualName>
        <ritualController>Slow</ritualController>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="extend_slowfall">
        <name>Hourglass Ritual (Slowfall)</name>
        <desc>The hourglass ritual can be used to extend a buff to a significantly longer duration.  It adds 180 seconds plus an additional 180 seconds for each Buff Power modifier included in the same spell stage as the buff.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>wizardChalk</relatedEntries>
        <ritualName>hourglass</ritualName>
        <ritualController>Slowfall</ritualController>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="extend_swiftswim">
        <name>Hourglass Ritual (Swift Swim)</name>
        <desc>The hourglass ritual can be used to extend a buff to a significantly longer duration.  It adds 180 seconds plus an additional 180 seconds for each Buff Power modifier included in the same spell stage as the buff.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>wizardChalk</relatedEntries>
        <ritualName>hourglass</ritualName>
        <ritualController>SwiftSwim</ritualController>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="extend_truesight">
        <name>Hourglass Ritual (True Sight)</name>
        <desc>The hourglass ritual can be used to extend a buff to a significantly longer duration.  It adds 180 seconds plus an additional 180 seconds for each Buff Power modifier included in the same spell stage as the buff.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>wizardChalk</relatedEntries>
        <ritualName>hourglass</ritualName>
        <ritualController>TrueSight</ritualController>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="extend_waterbreathing">
        <name>Hourglass Ritual (Water Breathing)</name>
        <desc>The hourglass ritual can be used to extend a buff to a significantly longer duration.  It adds 180 seconds plus an additional 180 seconds for each Buff Power modifier included in the same spell stage as the buff.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>wizardChalk</relatedEntries>
        <ritualName>hourglass</ritualName>
        <ritualController>WaterBreathing</ritualController>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="extend_waterygrave">
        <name>Hourglass Ritual (Watery Grave)</name>
        <desc>The hourglass ritual can be used to extend a buff to a significantly longer duration.  It adds 180 seconds plus an additional 180 seconds for each Buff Power modifier included in the same spell stage as the buff.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>wizardChalk</relatedEntries>
        <ritualName>hourglass</ritualName>
        <ritualController>WateryGrave</ritualController>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="extend_shrink">
        <name>Hourglass Ritual (Shrink)</name>
        <desc>The hourglass ritual can be used to extend a buff to a significantly longer duration.  It adds 180 seconds plus an additional 180 seconds for each Buff Power modifier included in the same spell stage as the buff.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>wizardChalk</relatedEntries>
        <ritualName>hourglass</ritualName>
        <ritualController>Shrink</ritualController>
      </subitem>
	  <subitem id="call_rain">
        <name>Hourglass Ritual (Call Rain)</name>
        <desc>The hourglass ritual can be used to modify the banish rain spell to instead call rain forth.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>wizardChalk</relatedEntries>
        <ritualName>hourglass</ritualName>
        <ritualController>BanishRain</ritualController>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="recall_to_gateway">
        <name>Recall to Gateway</name>
        <desc>The ringed cross ritual can be used to re-target the Recall spell so you travel to a specified gateway instead of your marked location.  The three runes used need to match a gateway combination.  The chalk and runes will be consumed as part of the teleportation.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>wizardChalk,warding_candle</relatedEntries>
        <ritualName>ringedCross</ritualName>
        <ritualController>Recall</ritualController>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="recall_other">
        <name>Recall Other</name>
        <desc>The ringed cross ritual can be used to re-target the Recall spell so you pull another player to you.  The combination can be obtained by the player using the True Sight spell, and can vary in length from player to player.  Be careful when giving out your player rune combination, as it can be used to target you specifically.  This recall also works cross-dimensionally.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>TrueSight,wizardChalk,warding_candle</relatedEntries>
        <ritualName>ringedCross</ritualName>
        <ritualController>Recall</ritualController>
      </subitem>
	  <subitem id="otherworldly_ritual">
        <name>Otherworldly Ritual</name>
        <desc>The ringed cross ritual can be used to re-activate an #5Inert Spawner#0 in an interesting way.  It causes the spawner to turn into an #5Otherworldly Aura#0!</desc>
        <relatedEntries>wizardChalk,warding_candle</relatedEntries>
        <ritualName>ringedCross</ritualName>
        <ritualController>Transplace</ritualController>
      </subitem>
      <relatedEntries>wizardChalk</relatedEntries>
    </ritual>
  </structures>
  <mobs>
    <mob id="MobHecate">
      <name>Hecate</name>
      <desc>The hecate is a dark spirit from the nether.  Occasionally, the walls between the Nether and the Overworld can weaken, allowing the Hecates to spawn in the overworld.  The hecate is an assassin - it moves extremely fast and can turn invisible briefly when attacking.  They deal a large amount of damage, but thankfully don't have much in terms of resilience  It's rumored that if you move slowly and quietly enough, you can pass by them undetected as long as you don't get too close.</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </mob>
    <mob id="MobManaElemental">
      <name>Mana Elemental</name>
      <desc>
				The mana elemental is a combination of vinteum shards
				held together by bolts of Etherium. They are towering
				creatures, often reaching 3m in height. They attack with
				bolts of raw mana that lash out, dealing minor damage
				but stealing mana, and return to the elemental, healing
				it based on the amount of mana stolen. They are highly
				resistant to physical damage. If all the mana is drained
				from the elemental, it will die.
			</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </mob>
    <mob id="MobManaCreeper">
      <name>Mana Creeper</name>
      <desc>
				The mana creeper is a variant on the normal creeper, but
				instead of a violent explosion, the mana creeper
				disintegrates into a mana vortex, which will drain the
				mana of everything nearby. The vortex grows the longer
				it lives, but luckily all of them don't last for more
				than a few seconds. The vortex drains more mana the more
				you have, so it is still a threat to even the most
				powerful of magi.
			</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </mob>
    <mob id="MobLightMage">
      <name>Light Mage</name>
      <desc>
				Light magi are part of the white council. They are
				powerful mages who have dedicated themselves to the
				forces of light. They will heal friendly players and
				assist them in combat against the various enemies that
				plague the world of Minecraft. They have a special
				distaste for Dark Mages.
			</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </mob>
    <mob id="MobDarkMage">
      <name>Dark Mage</name>
      <desc>
				Dark magi are part of the Black Court. They are sinister
				casters who are capable of terrifying feats of magic.
				These feats come at a price though, dark magi are
				reviled and twisted beings. They will fight anything
				living except the undead (which tehnically aren't
				"living" anyways) and creepers. They will go out of
				their way to fight a Light Mage.
			</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </mob>
    <mob id="MobFireElemental">
      <name>Fire Elemental</name>
      <desc>
				Fire elementals are beings of pure fire. They are
				destructive and ignite anything in their path. Fire
				Elementals are only found in the nether.
			</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </mob>
    <mob id="MobWaterElemental">
      <name>Water Elemental</name>
      <desc>
				Water elementals are beings of pure water. They are
				found anywhere water is in abundance. They attack in
				groups, using water to push and pull their target. They
				can affect their targets with Watery Grave, which will
				pull unsuspecting down to the crushing black depths.
			</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </mob>
    <mob id="EarthElemental">
      <name>Earth Elemental</name>
      <desc>
				Earth elementals are found slumbering deep within caves.
				They are passive by nature, and boast an extreme
				resistance to physical damage. Combined with a high
				health pool, anyone learning to summon one could conjure
				up a veritable tank. Their attacks force the target to
				focus on them and they will try to bounce from target to
				target.
			</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </mob>
    <mob id="MobDryad">
      <name>Dryad</name>
      <desc>
				Dryads are peaceful creatures often found in forests and
				grasslands. They can be lured with a sapling and will
				periodically make nearby plants grow faster.
			</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </mob>
    <mob id="MobDarkling">
      <name>Darkling</name>
      <desc>Darklings are small dog-like creatures that are found in the nether.  Their body becomes less visible during night, fading to near invsibility at midnight.  As dawn approaches, the Darklings will begin to gradually appear again until they become fully visible again for the day.</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </mob>
    <mob id="HellCow">
      <name>Hell Cow</name>
      <desc>Moo? Moo moo moo, moo moo moo moo.  Moo.  Moo moo moo moo moo, moo moo moo?  Moo!  Moo moo moo moo moo - moo moo moo. !d 1.) Moo moo moo moo !d 2.) Moo, moo moo moo moo. !d 3.) Moo! !d Moo, moo moo moo, moo moo moo.  Moo moo moo moo moo moo.  Moo, moo!</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </mob>
    <mob id="Flicker">
      <name>Flickers</name>
      <desc>Flickers are lesser elementals from the various elemental planes that have crossed over into our world.  Their magical bond is tenuous at best and they are known for "Flicking" back and forth between their plane and ours.  They are the starting point for #5Ars Magica Automation#0. 
	  !d
			Flickers are timid by nature and will flick back to their own dimension if attacked, or if they feel threatened.  Giving them a modicum of magic in the form of #5some sort of lasting effect#0 makes them feel more comfortable and less likely to run away.  #5Flickers can be captured inside of a Flicker Jar#0.
			!d
			There is one type of flicker for each affinity.  Flickers of each affinity will behave differently.  For example, Air Flickers tend to like to stay higher above the ground, while Earth Flickers will prefer to stay low.
			!d
			Flickers of each affinity can be found near regions of the world that remind them of their affinity.			</desc>
      <subitem id="waterflicker">
        <name>Water Flicker</name>
        <desc>#5Water Flickers#0 will be found in areas that are predominantly water, like swmaps, rivers, and oceans.</desc>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="airflicker">
        <name>Air Flicker</name>
        <desc>#5Air Flickers#0 can be found anywhere not underground, and will fly around higher in the sky (~25 blocks above the ground).</desc>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="earthflicker">
        <name>Earth Flicker</name>
        <desc>#5Earth Flickers#0 can be found anywhere, but they prefer underground locations.  They will stay close to the ground.</desc>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="fireflicker">
        <name>Fire Flicker</name>
        <desc>#5Fire Flickers#0 can be found in the nether..</desc>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="lightningflicker">
        <name>Lightning Flicker</name>
        <desc>#5Lightning Flickers#0 can be found on beaches and over oceans in the sky, where storms like to form.  They can be found in all areas if it is storming.</desc>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="natureflicker">
        <name>Nature Flicker</name>
        <desc>#5Nature Flickers#0 can be found in forests.</desc>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="iceflicker">
        <name>Ice Flicker</name>
        <desc>#5Ice Flickers#0 can be found in frozen areas, such as Taiga.</desc>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="arcaneflicker">
        <name>Arcane Flicker</name>
        <desc>#5Arcane Flickers#0 can be found in magical areas.  They very much like Witchwood Forests.</desc>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="lifeflicker">
        <name>Life Flicker</name>
        <desc>#5Life Flickers#0 can be found anywhere.  Any flicker spawning has a small chance to be a life flicker rather than whatever else it could be.</desc>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="enderflicker">
        <name>Ender Flicker</name>
        <desc>#5Ender Flickers#0 are found in the end.  Occasionally, a teleporting Enderman can open a rift large enough for Ender Flickers to slip through.</desc>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="xycraftflicker">
        <name>XyCraft Flicker</name>
        <desc>#5XyCraft Flickers#0 are implemented, but don't do anything yet.</desc>
      </subitem>
      <relatedEntries>flicker_jar,flickerFocus,flickerHabitat,crystalMarkers</relatedEntries>
    </mob>
  </mobs>
  <bosses>
    <boss id="BossNatureGuardian">
      <name>Nature Guardian</name>
      <desc>The Nature Guardian is a fearsome opponent.  Boasting a deadly scythe and the skill to use it, only the most powerful or foolish would seek it out. The few who have survived an encounter state that it is just as dangerous at range as in melee, if not more. !l Recommended level: 60 !p Rumor has it that it appears to guard the servants of nature when enough are slain in quick succession.  Nature can be harsh, but it will not tolerate a massacre. !d  Warning: !l This is a very difficult boss that can take down even the most well geared players. </desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </boss>
    <boss id="BossEarthGuardian">
      <name>Earth Guardian</name>
      <desc>
				Formed out of a core of stone, the Earth Guardian is a
				hardy opponent that can withstand incredible amounts of
				physical attacks. With whirling attacks and strength of
				the earth itself, be prepared for a fight. !l
				Recommended level: 25 !p To summon the Earth Guardian,
				first build a 3x3 obsidian platform with a chiseled
				stone brick at the centre. On top of the obsidian, build
				an iron inlay ring. Off of each side, on the same level
				as the inlays, place a vinteum torch. Then throw in a
				blue topaz, an emerald, and a chimerite. !d Upon
				summoning, the Earth Guardian will cleave out a large
				area of the surrounding blocks, so it would be wise to
				summon somewhere other than your basement.
			</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </boss>
    <boss id="BossWaterGuardian">
      <name>Water Guardian</name>
      <desc>
				The guardian of water is a unique being. It is always in
				a state of fluidity, making it able to shrug off attacks
				occasionally. It is a trickster as well, flowing into
				copies of itself and attacking from ambush if one is
				fooled by the decoy. !l Recommended level: 10 !p The
				water guardian can be summoned by creating a redstone
				inlay circle in any biome that is predominantly water.
				Then, while raining, throw a boat and a bucket of water
				into the circle as homage to the many ships lost at sea.
			</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </boss>
    <boss id="BossWinterGuardian">
      <name>Winter Guardian</name>
      <desc>
				The Winter Guardian is truly the embodiment of it's
				namesake. Surrounded by frigid winds that sap the
				strength of all who near it, the Winter Guardian pummels
				its frozen foes and shatters them with powerful strikes.
				!p To summon the Winter Guardian, seek out an area in
				the grips of winter. Place a gold inlay circle on the
				ground and build an effigy to the Winter Guardian in the
				centre, Ice on top of two Blue Topaz blocks. Then create
				3 snow golems close by to fuel the summoning. !d
				Warning: !l This is a very difficult boss that can take
				down even the most well geared players.
			</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </boss>
    <boss id="BossArcaneGuardian">
      <name>Arcane Guardian</name>
      <desc>
				A mage of ancient times, the Arcane Guardian has access
				to a wide variety of spells. From attacks to buffs to
				debuffs, prepare for a magical duel that will test your
				counterspell knowledge. Protected by a powerful sigil,
				the Arcane Guardian has as many tricks against melee
				opponents as it does against ranged attackers. !l Recommended level: 45 !p To
				summon the Arcane Guardian, first construct a Shrine of
				Knowledge. The shrine is 2 pillars of bookshelves, 3
				high, with a lectern on the ground in between them
				containing an Arcane Compendium. Place an iron inlay
				circle directly in front of the structure, and throw an
				Arcane Essence directly in the middle of the circle to
				start the ritual.
			</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </boss>
    <boss id="BossAirGuardian">
      <name>Air Guardian</name>
      <desc>
				The Air Guardian is a being of wind, and makes heavy use
				of knockback based attacks. It would be foolish to go
				into battle with one without some form of falling
				protection. The Air Guardian is a powerful ranged
				caster, but it requires a great deal of focus to finish
				some of it's spells... !l Recommended level: 35 !p To
				summon the Air Guardian, climb up well above the clouds
				and build a platform (y 150 or higher). Build a gold
				inlay ring on the platform and throw in an Air Essence.
			</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </boss>
    <boss id="BossFireGuardian">
      <name>Fire Guardian</name>
      <desc>
				The Fire Guardian is a living inferno from the depths of
				the nether. To summon it, create a gold inlay ring in
				the nether on top of obsidian with a coal block in the middle. Throw a water
				essence onto the coal and the fire
				guardian will appear. Be warned though, it does not take kindly to
				those that try to bring water to its domain. Be prepared
				for a fight! !l Recommended level: 90
			</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </boss>
    <boss id="BossLifeGuardian">
      <name>Life Guardian</name>
      <desc>The life guardian generally prefers to let the natural order of things take their course, not intervening unless a true sacriledge against life is performed.  Luckily (or unluckily, depending on how you look at it) for you, you have come up with a way to commit such an act.  Create a 5x5 ring using wizard's chalk, and place a warding candle in the center part of each side, on the outside of the ring (4 candles in total).  The circle will help to contain and focus the deed.  Then, on the night of a full moon, sacrifice a villager child inside the circle.  That should be enough to anger the life guardian to action. !d You monster you. !p The life guardian doesn't attack much on its own, though it may decide to throw you around a little.  It generally prefers to let others do the fighting for it, infusing them with its tremendous power.  In return, the others will often lay down their lives for the guardian's protection.  The life guardian is a different kind of fight than the other guardians.  !d Recommended level: 50</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </boss>
    <boss id="BossLightningGuardian">
      <name>Lightning Guardian</name>
      <desc>The lightning guardian is as unpredictable as it is powerful.  It can fire bolts of lightning at extreme range, and has been known to mess with the synapses inside the brains of living creatures.  It has also on occasion been able to replicate an effect similar to telekinesis using massive amounts of concentrated static electricity, which leaves the unfortunate victim open to several other effects. !d To summon the lightning guardian, create a #5Gold Inlay Ring#0 and place a mana battery in the middle.  Then, place 2 iron bars on top, creating a lightning rod.  !d  Finally, wait for a storm. !d This guardian is capable of doing extreme damage in a short amount of time.  Make sure you are well protected.  Recommended Level: 70</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </boss>
    <boss id="BossEnderGuardian">
      <name>Ender Guardian</name>
      <desc>Tales are told in hushed whispers of the true guardian of the End.  Of eyes glowing with an abhorrent light, and scaly skin as black as a moonless night.  Alas, the tales of this waking nightmare are vague at best and always shrouded in the veil of speculation.  The truth is, nobody has ever seen the guardian and lived.  The most common tale is that of Magnus Severinus, the Archmage of the Second Era.  At the height of his power, he was rumored to be able to move mountains with a thought, create lush gardens out of the most barren terrain, and create wards that could stop an army cold.  Alas, his most trusted advisor took ill, and her spiteful stepson had taken her place.  Goaded by honeyed words encouraging his power and making him arrogant, he gathered the conclave together and in front of them all, tore open the fabric between worlds, opening a portal to the end that pulsed with a soft purple glow that almost seemed to draw light away from its surroundings.  He stepped in, and summoned the guardian.  He never had time to scream.  A piece of paper, flecked with bits of dark blood, flitted back through the portal and it winked shut.  Upon the paper was the following ritual: !d In the End, around a black aurem atop a platform of blackest coal, create an inlay of gold.  Light a burning fire on each side of the inlay.  Throw in an Ender Essence and an Eye of Ender to destabilize the aurem and summon the guardian. !d The paper was locked away in magical valuts and forgotten for millenia...until now.</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </boss>
  </bosses>
  <blocks>
    <block id="illusionBlocks">
      <name>Illusion Blocks</name>
      <desc>
			Illusion blocks are so realistic that your brain will not allow you to walk through them due to self preservation and common sense.  Only with true sight can you convince yourself that the illusion is not real, and pass through to the other side.
			!l
			"Is that it?"
			!l
			"No. That's a wall."
			!l
			"It could be disguised."
			!l
			"You're not very good at looking for things, are you?"
			!l
			"I'm good at looking for walls. Look, I found another one."
			</desc>
      <subitem id="illusionBlock@0">
        <name>Illusion Block</name>
        <desc>Standard illusion blocks will look and function as solid blocks unless the entity attempting to pass through has #9True Sight#0 active.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>illusionBlock@1,everstone</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="illusionBlock@1">
        <name>Ethereal Illusion Block</name>
        <desc>Ethereal illusion blocks will look like solid blocks, but anything can pass through them.  They still will emit particles if you have #9True Sight#0 active.  Ethereal Illusion Blocks will not change their appearance due to True Sight though.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>illusionBlock@0,everstone</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </block>
    <block id="essence_refiner">
      <name>Essence Refiner</name>
      <desc>
				The essence refiner takes everyday items and using
				#5Arcane Ash#0, refines them into a pure representation
				of their parts, known as #5essences#0. The recipes for
				specific essences can be found under #9Items -&gt;
				Essences#0. The essence refiner also requires #2Etherium#0 to function.
				Neutral Etherium can be obtained from an #9Obelisk#0, which has no specific advantages or
				drawbacks. Finally, Dark Etherium can be used from a
				#9Black Aurem#0, which significantly reduces the amount
				of time it takes to refine the essence. The spinning ring
				on the UI will shift from blue to purple as the
				refinement process progresses and eventually completes.
				A flashing red ring means there is insufficient Etherium to
				continue, and the process has been paused.
			</desc>
      <relatedEntries>essence</relatedEntries>
    </block>
    <block id="essenceconduit">
      <name>Etherium Conduit</name>
      <desc>
				Infused with dusts to direct Etherium through the 
				air, the Etherium Conduit began seeing heavy use almost 
				immediately after its invention.  They can be used to 
				transfer Etherium over longer distances than the direct 
				range of Etherium generation apparatus.  Each one has a 
				range of 10 blocks, and can form chains to move Etherium 
				up to 100 blocks away from the origin.
			</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </block>
    <block id="casters">
      <name>Caster Blocks</name>
      <desc>
				A spell is nothing more than directed essence. The will
				of a magic user dictates what the essence does, and if
				they have enough capacity for essence, the magic will
				flow forth. The caster was designed to replicate that
				ability, converting raw essence into a burst of magic
				that is directed through a spell focus (as well as the
				occasional mana focus) and shaped via the instructions
				on a spell scroll. Because of the extreme essence draw
				of certain spells, the internal crystals were fitted
				with a slot to allow a charge focus which causes the
				amount of incoming essence to be increased
				substantially. Alternately, a mana focus can be fitted
				into the same slots, causing the internal essence
				routing to be much more efficient.
			</desc>
      <subitem id="casterRune">
        <name>Caster Rune</name>
        <desc>The Caster Rune functions in the same way as a #5Caster#0, save for one specific difference:  The caster rune does not required a redstone signal to operate, and rather casts when walked upon.  It will cast directly on whatever triggers it.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>foci</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="blockcaster">
        <name>Caster</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>foci</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <relatedEntries>foci</relatedEntries>
    </block>
    <block id="blockseerstone">
      <name>Seer Stone</name>
      <desc>
				Operating on a similar principle as the Astral Barrier,
				the Seer Stone uses an Etherium aura projected through a
				spell focus to detect nearby objects. It can be
				controlled by focusing the Etherium to a particular type
				of object, and the resonant frequency of the Etherium can
				be dictated with the use of a rune combination. Without the use
				of a rune combination, the resonant frequency fluxuates
				unpredictably and cannot be avoided. The seer stone,
				however, is meant for a more subtle approach, letting
				the object continue, but emitting a small signal that
				often activates much more powerful defenses. By sneaking
				up and activating the stone, one can even (if he has the
				correct key of course) cause the stone to invert its
				detection methods, detecting those with the matching
				keystone combination.
				!d
				Different #5Foci#0 can be used in the Seer Stone.  #5Lesser, 
				Standard, and Greater foci#0 change the detection distance of 
				the stone (5, 10, or 15 blocks respectively), while #5Item, 
				Player, Monster, or Creature foci#0 can
				change what the seer stone is looking for.  Without a target
				focus and a distance focus, the seer stone will not function.
				!d
				A keystone is 
				searched for in the case of a player.  If the player has a
				keystone in their inventory matching the rune combination in
				the seer stone, the seer stone will ignore them and will not
				trigger.
			</desc>
      <relatedEntries>lesserfocus,standardfocus,greaterfocus,item_focus,player_focus,monster_focus,creature_focus,keystone,foci</relatedEntries>
    </block>
    <block id="blockastralbarrier">
      <name>Astral Barrier</name>
      <desc>
				When walking the void, one must be aware of barriers.
				Projecting an Etherium aura through a spell focus, these
				barriers resonate at a specific magical frequency,
				dictated by a keytstone. Without the proper matching
				keystone, these barriers will destabilize your magics
				and force you out of the void. Should the astral barrier
				not have a keystone present, its magic frequency will
				fluxuate unpredictably, and no amount of Keystones can
				protect you from its effects. Several Dark Magi raids
				have been foiled and several Light Magi have been
				captured due to their failure to spot the barrier in
				time.
				!d
				Different #5Foci#0 can be used in the Astral Barrier.  #5Lesser, 
				Standard, and Greater foci#0 change the distance of 
				the barrier, to 5, 10, or 15 blocks respectively. Without
				a distance focus, the barrier will not function.
				!d
				The barrier will stop teleportation into its radius, including
				ender pearls, blink, mark/recall, and endermen.
			</desc>
      <relatedEntries>lesserfocus,standardfocus,greaterfocus,keystone,foci</relatedEntries>
    </block>
    <block id="blockkeystonerecepticle">
      <name>Keystone Recepticle</name>
      <desc>
				Not all magi are capable of walking the void as a means
				of travel, nor are all willing. The void is detectable,
				blockable. Gateways were developed by the Dark Magi
				early in the war, and it allowed them to take many Light
				Mage encampments by surprise, as it uses alternate
				pathways to transport to its destination. Astral
				Barriers were ineffective at stopping the arrival of the
				Dark Magi, and the destination gate required no power of
				its own. The Light Magi destroyed as many as they could
				find, but the Dark Magi only needed one. The only hope
				was when a young Light Mage by the name of Damien
				Callitri discovered that the gateways could be locked
				down if a Keystone was inserted into a flaw in the
				design at just the right spot in the gateway mechanism,
				and would actually cause the gateway to send the Dark
				Mages to a different gateway (or nowhere if none others
				existed that weren't locked down). This halted the raids
				completely, and allowed the White Magi to turn the tides
				back in their favour, as they could actually use the
				gateways to return to their keystone gate. The design
				flaw became jokingly known as the "Keystone Recepticle"
				amongst the White Magi.
			</desc>
      <relatedEntries>keystone,gateways</relatedEntries>
    </block>
    <block id="ores@0">
      <name>Vinteum Ore</name>
      <desc>
				Vinteum was discovered during a heated battle between
				the Light and Dark magi when a stray arcane bolt
				collided with an ender bolt. The resulting explosion
				created a crater several meters deep, where a sparkling
				blue ore shimmered in the light of the afternoon. It
				appears to have no magical properties of its own, but
				when heat is applied, it becomes a fine dust with an
				exceptional capacity to conduct Etherium. As such, it is
				widely used in magical contraptions all over the world.
			</desc>
      <relatedEntries>itemOre@0,vinteumTorch,warding_candle</relatedEntries>
    </block>
    <block id="mana_battery">
      <name>Mana Battery</name>
      <desc>
				Drawing further on vinteum dust's ability to conduct
				Etherium, a small group of brilliant magi created a frame
				out of iron and gold which is capable of storing massive
				amounts of Etherium. Mana batteries will
				always provide power to connected devices, but they can
				also request Etherium from the network
				when given a redstone signal.
			</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </block>
    <block id="cerublossom">
      <name>Cerublossom</name>
      <desc>
				Cerublossom flowers thrive in lush, green environments. They
				were one of the first magical plants discovered, being
				used in potions and salves. Cerublossom emits a
				faint sparkling glow of light around it as well, and was
				used just as much for decoration as an alchemical
				ingredient. A short while after its discovery, it was
				also noted that the Cerublossom could be used as part of
				the purification process for Vinteum dust.
			</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </block>
    <block id="desert_nova">
      <name>Desert Nova</name>
      <desc>
				Desert Novas grow in dry conditions. They get their name
				from the small bursts of magic that they periodically
				emit. The Nova has extraordinary magical properties for
				a desert plant, and is highly sought after. It is one of
				the two plants used in the purification process of
				Vinteum dust.
			</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </block>
    <block id="keystonechest">
      <name>Keystone Chest</name>
      <desc>The keystone chest was developed as a simple way to have a magically locked chest.  When a keystone is inserted into the internal slot, in order to open it, one must have a matching keystone in their hand.  By inserting the keystone into the outer lock*, the chest can be opened.  If there is no keystone, the chest opens normally.
			!l
			!l
			* Just right click the chest with the keystone in your hand.</desc>
      <relatedEntries>keystone</relatedEntries>
    </block>
    <block id="magicWall">
      <name>Magic Wall</name>
      <desc>An early attempt at the illusion block, the magic wall wasn't really able to blend with it's surroundings.  Or even prevent people from looking through.  The value, though, was just after having master mage Leonidus criticize us for our efforts, watching him walk face first into one.  That's when we knew it at least had the stopping power part right.  But when the fireball he threw at it BOUNCED back and burnt his beard off, we knew it was a keeper.</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </block>
    <block id="arcanereconstructor">
      <name>Arcane Reconstructor</name>
      <desc>Magic can, with the right influence, do anything.  By directing Etherium at the weak spots in otherwise mundane items, the Etherium will solidify to repair the damage, making it good as new.</desc>
      <relatedEntries>chargefocus,arcane_deconstructor</relatedEntries>
    </block>
    <block id="lectern">
      <name>Lectern</name>
      <desc>A must have for any organized mage, the Lectern is an ideal place to store books, compendiums, and thaumonomicons for easy access.  The book sits perfectly where it can be read without having to remove it from the lectern.  It is also a critical part of the Crafting Altar, as spell crafting does require organization.</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </block>
    <block id="occulus" unlocked="true">
      <name>Occulus</name>
      <desc>A gateway to the stars, the Occulus shows you your innermost self.  It is here that you can spend skill points to unlock new shapes, components, and modifiers.  There are 3 kinds of skill points, which can be learned by obtaining Infinity Orbs from Dungeons, other worldgen, and Summoning Rituals.  The skills, when learnable, will glow with the corresponding skill point needed to unlock it.  Blue are the most common skill points, followed by Green, and finally Red.</desc>
      <relatedEntries>inscriptionTable,lectern,unlockingPowers</relatedEntries>
    </block>
    <block id="calefactor">
      <name>Calefactor</name>
      <desc>A magical furnace, the calefactor can produce vinteum dust as it cooks in addition to the smelted item.  If provided with light, neutral, and dark etherium, the calefactor can double ores.  It always has a small chance to double food.</desc>
      <relatedEntries>foci,manafocus,chargefocus</relatedEntries>
    </block>
    <block id="inscriptionTable">
      <name>Inscription Table</name>
      <desc>Organization is a must for any mage who wants to be successful.  Using this table along with a writable book, you can compose spells of incredible power.  Most mages will lay out what spell parts they know at the top of the table in the Source Region, and will drag shapes and modifiers to the brown squares set aside for Shape Groups, and components to the Spell Grammar section at the bottom to lay out a spell.  Once satisfied with the spell, you can write the spells down in a writable book (you did remember to bring one, didn't you?).  This book can be placed upon a lectern that is part of the Crafting Altar structure, and will guide you through the process needed to make the spell.  The book is worth reading too, as it contains a recap of the spell you will be creating, a materials list, and an affinity breakdown.  See #5Guides -&gt; Your First Spell#0 for more detailed information.</desc>
      <relatedEntries>altarOfCreation,craftingAltar,magiciansWorkbench,spellComponents101,spell_parchment,inscriptionUpgrades</relatedEntries>
    </block>
    <block id="particleEmitter" unlocked="true">
      <name>Particle Emitter</name>
      <desc>Purely a decoration block, the particle emitter can be used to create a magical feel in any area.  The emitter can be customized by right clicking it, and it can be hidden.  If hidden, simply holding a crystal wrench while near it will cause it to be visible again.  Right clicking a particle emitter with a crystal wrench will cause its settings to be copied.  Right clicking another particle emitter will copy those settings to the second emitter.</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </block>
    <block id="aum">
      <name>Aum</name>
      <desc>A flower with healing properties, Aum is a component in many spells.  It can only be found at the base of witchwood trees.</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </block>
    <block id="tarmaroot">
      <name>Tarma Root</name>
      <desc>Lighter than it looks, Tarma Root grows in caves and other dark places.  It is an ingredient in spells, and air essences.</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </block>
    <block id="wakebloom">
      <name>Wakebloom</name>
      <desc>Growing on the surface of water in warm climates, wakebloom is used in water-based spells frequently as well as being a component in water essence.</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </block>
    <block id="summoner">
      <name>Summoner</name>
      <desc>The summoner takes Etherium one step farther and uses it to summon creatures to do your bidding upon receipt of a redstone signal.  It has a hefty summon cost, as well as a maintain cost to keep the summon alive.  If the redstone signal ever dies out or power runs out, the creature will unsummon.  When the creature is unsummoned or killed, there is a short delay before it can be summoned again.  Note that the summoner requires a full-fledged summon spell, not a filled crystal phylactery.</desc>
      <relatedEntries>crystal_phylactery,chargefocus,manafocus,foci</relatedEntries>
    </block>
    <block id="inlays">
      <name>Inlays</name>
      <desc>Inlays are runes that are used both for decoration and for summoning bosses when placed into the right pattern (see Structures).  There are a few different types of Inlay.</desc>
      <subitem id="redstone_inlay">
        <name>Redstone Inlay</name>
        <desc>Redstone inlays are the most basic of inlay.  They are used to summon bosses, and can also be used as rails.  They will speed up a minecart as it passes over them.  Be wary when cornering too fast, as the cart can leave the tracks entirely.</desc>
        <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="iron_inlay">
        <name>Iron Inlay</name>
        <desc>Iron inlays are an intermediate inlay.  They are used to summon bosses, and can also be used as rails.  When a minecart touches an iron inlay, it will reverse direction.  Some of the momentum is preserved, but not all.</desc>
        <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="gold_inlay">
        <name>Gold Inlay</name>
        <desc>Gold inlays are the most advanced inlay.  They are used to summon the most powerful of bosses.  They can also be used as rails.  When a minecart touches a gold inlay, it will attempt to warp to the next gold inlay in the direction it is currently traveling within 8 blocks.  This can transport the minecart (and any passengers) through solid obstacles, as it is in fact teleportation.  There is a short delay before the minecart can teleport on a gold rail again after it warps.</desc>
        <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </block>
    <block id="stonebricksmooth@3" unlocked="true">
      <name>Chiseled Stone Blocks</name>
      <desc>You can create chiseled stone blocks that you need by crafting 4 stone bricks together in a 2x2 grid.</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </block>
    <block id="saplingWitchwood">
      <name>Witchwood Saplings</name>
      <desc>Witchwood saplings can rarely be obtained from the leaves of a witchwood tree.  They can be planted, however they need a source of Liquid Etherium within 1 block and below them (x/z +/- 1, y-1).  The more liquid etherium source pools nearby (max 8), the faster the sapling will grow.  Even with all 8, however, the grow time can be significant.  Once the sapling grows into a full witchwood tree, it can sometimes also cause aum to grow nearby as well.</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </block>
    <block id="altarOfCreation">
      <name>Crafting Altar</name>
      <desc>Harnessing the forces of creation, the crafting altar allows mages to work miracles of magic.  This is where you will create all of your spells in AM2.  The crafting altar is a component of a #9multiblock structure#0.
			</desc>
      <relatedEntries>runes,yourFirstSpell,gainingMagicLevels,obelisk,otherworldly_aura</relatedEntries>
    </block>
    <block id="magiciansWorkbench">
      <name>Magician's Workbench</name>
      <desc>The magician's workbench was born out of necessity from the large number of items mages tend to make.  However, one particular mage got tired of having to clear out the crafting grid every time he forgot a sub-component, and having to run to a chest, usually dropping items along the way.  This table #5has multiple crafting grids#0 that you can use simultaneously to make items.  It also remembers previous crafting recipes (the most recent 8) and can restore that recipe to the crafting grid with the click of a button, provided the components are in its #5internal storage#0.  There is an upgrade you can craft that will increase the size of the second grid to a 3x3 from a 2x2.</desc>
      <relatedEntries>workbenchUpgrade</relatedEntries>
    </block>
    <block id="everstone" unlocked="true">
      <name>Everstone</name>
      <desc>Everstone is a magically-infused block that can mimic other blocks much like #5illusion blocks#0 can.  However, when broken, Everstone will #9not drop, but rather become incorporeal for a brief time#0.  After that time, it will re-solidify and return to its original state.  While it is solidifying, everstone can be passed through as if it is not there.  To make it mimic a block, simply right click on the everstone with the desired block in hand.  If it is not already mimicing a block, it will assume the properties of the new block.  To remove the mask, simply right click the everstone with a #5Crystal Wrench#0.  Right clicking an everstone that is not already mimicing a texture will cause it to drop as normal and be recovered.</desc>
      <relatedEntries>illusionBlock@0,illusionBlock@1</relatedEntries>
    </block>
    <block id="vinteumTorch">
      <name>Vinteum Torches</name>
      <desc>Vinteum Torches are crafted in a simplistic way, and glow with roughly the same brightness as a standard torch.  They are just an aesthetic alternative.</desc>
      <relatedEntries>ores</relatedEntries>
    </block>
    <block id="slipstreamGenerator">
      <name>Slipstream Generator</name>
      <desc>You have managed to create a device that can project a cushion of air around you to make you float upwards or gently lower down towards the ground.  The machine only works on mages above it (#5players only#0), but has a large vertical range.  In testing, you note that if you are falling when you enter its effect radius, it takes a little while before it can completely catch you.  You have also managed to make it work #9based on the direction you are looking#0.  Look up, go up.  Look down, go down.  Look forward, hover.  You can also #9sneak to remain vertically stationary#0, regardless of where you are looking.</desc>
    </block>
    <block id="obelisk">
      <name>Obelisk</name>
      <desc>The Obelisk is a runed block that is used to generate #5Etherium#0 (the power system in Ars Magica 2).  It acts as a magical furnace, and burns Vinteum Dust or Liquid Etherium to generate power.
			!d
			It can be altered using #9Rituals#0 to become a #4Black Aurem#0 or a #9Celestial Prism#0.</desc>
      <relatedEntries>obelisk_structure,blackaurem_structure,celestialprism_structure,essenceAllAround,powerTypes,mana_battery,essence_refiner,essenceconduit,casters,arcanereconstructor,slipstreamGenerator,crystal_wrench</relatedEntries>
    </block>
    <block id="brokenLink">
      <name>Broken Power Links</name>
      <desc>If a power path is created, and at some point a relay (conduits, etc.) or generator (obelisk, prism, aurem, etc.) is broken, the power system will attempt to let you know that there was something there, and something is amiss.  These blocks will be placed automatically by the power system if a broken link is detected.  The block will be placed at the point where the relay or generator used to be.
			!d
			These blocks will only ever be placed where no other block exists.  They cannot be broken by hand, but can be replaced with any block.  Broken power link blocks are only visible if you are wearing a pair of #9Magitech's Goggles#0.</desc>
      <relatedEntries>magitechGoggles</relatedEntries>
    </block>
    <block id="flickerHabitat">
      <name>Flicker Habitat</name>
      <desc>The flicker habitat is a series of crystals designed to allow Flickers to remain in our world.  If a #9Flicker Focus#0 is added, the flickers inside the focus will use the habitat to perform several tasks around the area, such as growing plants, sorting items, fishing, creating magical barriers, and many other functions.
			!d
			You can also place a #9Flicker Jar#0 in the habitat and it will serve to modify the functionality of adjacent habitats with a Flicker Focus in them.
			!d
			See the flicker focus entries for more information on how they can be modified.</desc>
      <relatedEntries>flickerFocus,flicker_jar,crystalMarkers</relatedEntries>
    </block>
    <block id="crystalMarker">
      <name>Crystal Markers</name>
      <desc>Crystal Markers are used to instruct Flickers inside of a Flicker Habitat on how to sort items.  When wearing #9Magitech Goggles#0, you can see the priority level of the different crystals.  This priority indicates the order in which the flickers will attempt to move items.  Lower priority crystals are tried first.  You can change the priority of any crystal by rght clicking it while holding a #9Magitech's Staff#0.</desc>
      <subitem id="crystalMarker@0">
        <name>Import Crystal</name>
        <desc>This crystal instructs the flickers to collect items from the inventory it is attached to and bring it into the item transportation network.  Import crystals cannot have a priority level.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>flickerFocus,crystal_wrench</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="crystalMarker@1">
        <name>Export Crystal</name>
        <desc>This crystal instructs the flickers that all items in the item transportation network can be exported to the inventory this crystal is attached to.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>flickerFocus,spell_staff_magitech,magitechGoggles,crystal_wrench</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="crystalMarker@2">
        <name>Mimic Export Crystal</name>
        <desc>This crystal instructs the flickers that items maybe exported from the item transportation network to the inventory this crystal is attached to so long as the inventory already contains that item.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>flickerFocus,spell_staff_magitech,magitechGoggles,crystal_wrench</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="crystalMarker@3">
        <name>Set Export Crystal</name>
        <desc>This crystal instructs the flickers that items may be exported from the item transportation network to the inventory this crystal is attached to so long as the item has been set through this crystal's GUI.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>flickerFocus,spell_staff_magitech,magitechGoggles,crystal_wrench</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="crystalMarker@4">
        <name>Regulate Export Crystal</name>
        <desc>This crystal instructs the flickers that items may be exported from the item transportation network to the inventory this crystal is attached to so long as the item has been set through this crystal's GUI and the inventory contains less then number of items set in the crystal's GUI.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>flickerFocus,spell_staff_magitech,magitechGoggles,crystal_wrench</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="crystalMarker@5">
        <name>Regulate Bidirectional Crystal</name>
        <desc>This crystal instructs the flickers that they may both import and export from the inventory this crystal is attached to !d Import: !l Flickers will take items from the inventory so long as the item has been added to this crystal's GUI and the number of items in the chest is greater then the number set in the GUI !d Export: !l Flickers will put items into the inventory so long as the item has been added to this crystal's GUI and the number of items is below the number set in the GUI.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>flickerFocus,spell_staff_magitech,magitechGoggles,crystal_wrench</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="crystalMarker@6">
        <name>Set Import Crystal</name>
        <desc>This crystal instructs the flickers that they may import items into the item transportation network from the inventory this crystal is attached to so long as the item has been added to this crystal's GUI.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>flickerFocus,spell_staff_magitech,magitechGoggles,crystal_wrench</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
	  <subitem id="crystalMarker@7">
        <name>Final Export Crystal</name>
        <desc>This crystal instructs the flickers that they should put any items that can't otherwise be placed in the inventory marked by this crystal.  These crystals always have the highest priority number, meaning items will be placed there last.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>flickerFocus,spell_staff_magitech,magitechGoggles,crystal_wrench</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
	  <subitem id="crystalMarker@8">
        <name>Spell Export Crystal</name>
        <desc>This crystal instructs the flickers to watch any crafting altar within 10 blocks. If it is crafting a spell, the flickers will attempt to fetch the next item required for the spell and place it in the inventory marked by this crystal.</desc>
        <relatedEntries>flickerFocus,spell_staff_magitech,magitechGoggles,crystal_wrench</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
    </block>
    <block id="keystoneDoors">
      <name>Keystone Doors</name>
      <desc>Keystone Doors can be locked using a rune combination.  If locked, they will only open if you have a keystone with the matching key in your inventory.  If not locked, they function simply as a door.  Zombies cannot break them down either way.</desc>
      <subitem id="keystoneDoor">
        <name>Keystone Door</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>keystone, keystoneTrapdoor</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="keystoneTrapdoor">
        <name>Keystone Trapdoor</name>
        <desc></desc>
        <relatedEntries>keystone, keystoneDoor</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
    </block>
    <block id="armor_infuser_index">
      <name>Armor Imbuement Table</name>
      <desc>The Armor Imbuement Table can be used to attach special imbuements to any armor in Minecraft.  In order to do this, you first need to have the armor equipped.  Mousing over any armor will display a prompt of "Press SHIFT for more information".  Doing so will show you how much XP has been absorbed into the armor.  Armor gains XP when you do.  See #5Mechanics -&gt; Armor XP Infusion#0 for more information on how it works. !d Once your armor has reached at least level 30, you can apply a Tier I imbuement to it.  Simply equip the armor and activate the Armor Imbuement Table.  Place the armor from the equip slots at the bottom of the UI into the active slot.  Available imbuements will appear in colour, unavailable ones will be grayscale.  You can only apply one tier of imbuement per armor piece, so choose wisely!  !d The tier costs are: !l Tier 1: 30 levels !l Tier 2: 42 levels !l Tier 3: 54 levls !l Tier 4: 66 levels !d Each time you imbue the armor, XP is deducted from it to apply the imbuement.</desc>
	  <subitem id="armor_infuser">
		<name>Block Recipe</name>
		<desc></desc>
		<relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
	  </subitem>
      <subitem id="imbuement_burnout_reduction">
        <name>Imbuement:  Burnout Reduction</name>
        <desc>The Burnout Reduction imbuement grants a 150% increase in the rate that your Burnout reduces. The effect is additive for each piece, with a maximum of 600%. !d Available Slots:  Head, Chest, Legs, Boots</desc>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="imbuement_fall_damage">
        <name>Imbuement: Fall Damage</name>
        <desc>The Fall Damage Imbuement causes a 15% reduction in fall damage. !d Available Slots:  Head, Chest, Legs, Boots</desc>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="imbuement_drown_damage">
        <name>Imbuement: Drown Damage</name>
        <desc>The Drown Damage Imbuement causes a 15% reduction in drown damage. !d Available Slots:  Head, Chest, Legs, Boots</desc>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="imbuement_explosive_damage">
        <name>Imbuement: Explosive Damage</name>
        <desc>The Explosive Damage Imbuement causes a 15% reduction in explosive damage. !d Available Slots:  Head, Chest, Legs, Boots</desc>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="imbuement_phys_damage">
        <name>Imbuement: Physical Damage</name>
        <desc>The Physical Damage Imbuement causes a 15% reduction in physical damage. !d Available Slots:  Head, Chest, Legs, Boots</desc>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="imbuement_fire_damage">
        <name>Imbuement: Fire Damage</name>
        <desc>The Fire Damage Imbuement causes a 15% reduction in fire damage. !d Available Slots:  Head, Chest, Legs, Boots</desc>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="imbuement_frost_damage">
        <name>Imbuement: Frost Damage</name>
        <desc>The Frost Damage Imbuement causes a 15% reduction in frost damage. !d Available Slots:  Head, Chest, Legs, Boots</desc>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="imbuement_lightning_damage">
        <name>Imbuement: Lightning Damage</name>
        <desc>The Lightning Damage Imbuement causes a 15% reduction in lightning damage. !d Available Slots:  Head, Chest, Legs, Boots</desc>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="imbuement_magic_damage">
        <name>Imbuement: Magic Damage</name>
        <desc>The Magic Damage Imbuement causes a 15% reduction in magic damage. !d Available Slots:  Head, Chest, Legs, Boots</desc>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="imbuement_mana_regeneration">
        <name>Imbuement: Mana Regeneration</name>
        <desc>The Mana Regeneration Imbuement grants a 10% increase to your mana regeneration rate. !d Available Slots: Head, Chest, Legs, Boots</desc>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="imbuement_magitech">
        <name>Imbuement: Magitech Goggles</name>
        <desc>The Magitech Goggles Imbuement causes any helmet to grant the same attributes as the #5Magitech Goggles#0. !d Available Slots: Head</desc>
        <relatedEntries>magitechGoggles</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="imbuement_pinpoint_ores">
        <name>Imbuement: Pinpoint Ores</name>
        <desc>The Pinpoint Ores Imbuement allows an extra level of precision when using a #5Warding Candle#0, causing the flame to go black when within 2 blocks of the target ore.  !d Available Slots: Head</desc>
        <relatedEntries>warding_candle</relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="imbuement_hunger_regen">
        <name>Imbuement: Hunger Regeneration</name>
        <desc>The Hunger Regeneration Imbuement causes your hunger to passively regenerate. !d Available Slots: Head</desc>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="imbuement_mining_speed">
        <name>Imbuement: Mining Speed</name>
        <desc>The Mining Speed Imbuemnt causes you to mine blocks 50% faster. !d Available Slots: Head</desc>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="imbuement_thaumic_vision">
        <name>Imbuement: Thaumic Vision</name>
        <desc>#9REQUIRES THAUMCRAFT#0 !d The Thaumic Vision Imbuement causes you to see things as if you had Thaumcraft Goggles equipped. !d Available Slots: Head</desc>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="imbuement_water_breathing">
        <name>Imbuement: Water Breathing</name>
        <desc>The Water Breathing Imbuement allows you to breathe underwater for a short time if your air gets low. !d Available Slots: Head</desc>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="imbuement_flicker_lure">
        <name>Imbuement: Flicker Lure</name>
        <desc>The Flicker Lure Imbuement will cause #9Flickers#0 to not flick away when you get close. !d Available Slots: Chest</desc>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="imbuement_soulbound">
        <name>Imbuement: Soulbound</name>
        <desc>The Soulbound Imbuement will cause the item to stay with you when you die rather than being dropped. !d Available Slots: Chest, Legs, Boots</desc>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="imbuement_healing">
        <name>Imbuement: Healing</name>
        <desc>The Healing Imbuement causes you go get a powerful regeneration buff if your health gets low. !d Available Slots: Chest</desc>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="imbuement_life_saving">
        <name>Imbuement: Life-Saving</name>
        <desc>The Life Saving Imbuement will reverse death on you, causing it to not apply and restoring 50% of your health.  Causes extreme damage to armor and has a long cooldown. !d Available Slots: Chest</desc>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="imbuement_bonus_xp">
        <name>Imbuement: Bonus Magic XP</name>
        <desc>The Bonus Magic XP Imbuement grants 50% bonus magic XP from spell casts. !d Available Slots: Chest</desc>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="imbuement_recoil">
        <name>Imbuement: Recoil</name>
        <desc>The Recoil Imbuement causes any melee attacker to be violently thrown backwards away from you. !d Available Slots: Chest</desc>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="imbuement_stepassist">
        <name>Imbuement: Step Assist</name>
        <desc>The Step Assist Imbuement allows you to step up over 1-block edges. !d Available Slots: Legs</desc>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="imbuement_dispelling">
        <name>Imbuement: Dispelling</name>
        <desc>The Dispelling Imbuement removes any negative buff applied to you.  Has a short cooldown. !d Available Slots: Legs</desc>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="imbuement_lava_prot">
        <name>Imbuement: Lava Protection</name>
        <desc>Should you fall into lava, this imbuement will proc, solidifying the lava around you into a protective dome of cobble/obsidian. !d Available Slots: Legs</desc>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="imbuement_jump_boost">
        <name>Imbuement: Jump Boost</name>
        <desc>The Jump Boost Imbuement allows you to jump significantly higher. !d Available Slots: Legs</desc>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="imbuement_swim_boost">
        <name>Imbuement: Swim Speed Boost</name>
        <desc>The Swim Speed Boost Imbuement allows you to swim significantly faster. !d Available Slots: Legs</desc>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="imbuement_run_speed">
        <name>Imbuement: Run Speed Boost</name>
        <desc>The Run Speed Boost Imbuement allows you to run significantly faster. !d Available Slots: Boots</desc>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="imbuement_fall_protection">
        <name>Imbuement: Fall Protection</name>
        <desc>The Fall Protection Imbuement will automatically apply a slowfall effect to you right before you hit the ground, preventing all damage.  It has a short cooldown. !d Available Slots: Boots</desc>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="imbuement_freedom">
        <name>Imbuement: Freedom of Movement</name>
        <desc>The Freedom of Movement Imbuement prevents most movement impairing effects from affecting you. !d Available Slots: Boots</desc>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="imbuement_water_walking">
        <name>Imbuement: Water Walking</name>
        <desc>You can walk on water with these boots.  You're a ninja! !d Water walking is only applied when you're on top of the water.  If you're in, or under the water, you can swim as normal.  Simply swim to the top of the water and jump out to start water walking.  From the top of the water, start sneaking to drop down into the depths. !d Available Slots: Boots</desc>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="imbuement_light_step">
        <name>Imbuement: Light Step</name>
        <desc>The Light Step Imbuement automatically causes a mage light to be placed at your feet (if possible) wherever the light level is low enough for monsters to spawn. !d Available Slots: Boots</desc>
      </subitem>
    </block>
	<block id="flicker_lure">
      <name>Flicker Lure</name>
      <desc>Flickers aren't normally able to enter our world, but with a little help and incentive, you can make that happen.  Placing this block and powering it with Etherium will allow flickers to be pulled into our world!  When you want them, just apply a redstone signal.  The type of flicker will depend on where the lure is.  See the entry on #9Flickers#0 for information on where to find specific ones.</desc>
      <relatedEntries>Flicker</relatedEntries>
    </block>
	<block id="arcane_deconstructor">
      <name>Arcane Deconstructor</name>
      <desc>The Arcane Deconstructor, when powerd with #5Dark Etherium#0 can disassemble an item back into its crafting components. !d  Oh yeah, it can also disassemble spells.  You will get most of the items back from a spell, but items such as the initial blank rune or etherium investments, as well as the final spell parchment, will not be refunded. !d The deconstructor will attempt to place items into adjacent inventories if its own is full upon un-crafting.  Any items that cannot be placed are simply ejected into the world.</desc>
      <relatedEntries>chargefocus</relatedEntries>
    </block>
	<block id="otherworldly_aura">
      <name>Otherworldly Aura</name>
      <desc>The Otherworldly Aura is used to automate spell creation.  It summons a shadow copy of whoever created it to complete the spell.  !d To use it, you need the following: !l -Within 10 blocks of the #5Crafting Altar#0 !l -#4Dark#0 or #9Neutral#0 Etherium (have a good amount on hand, interdimensional travel is costly!) !l -One or more block inventories (chest, hopper, etc) within 8 blocks of the Aura.  These inventories are what will be searched for spell reagents. !d The aurem will maintain the shadow for as long as needed, provided it has enough power.  Running out of power will cause the shadow to dissipate, and out of spite for the inconvenience, it may take whatever reagent it is currently carrying!  Only one aura will assist an altar at a time, so multiple auras are not needed. !d To get the aura, perform a #5Ritual of the Cross#0 around an #5Inert Spawner#0 with #5Transplace#0 as the catalyst.</desc>
      <relatedEntries>rituals_overview,Transplace,corruption_obelisk,inertSpawner</relatedEntries>
    </block>
	<block id="inertSpawner">
		<name>Inert Spawner</name>
		<desc>You've managed to pick up a monster spawner, but it seems to not be able to spawn anything anymore.  You should look into other applications for this device, or find a way to re-activate it. !d Perhaps #5Dark Etherium#0 and a #5Filled Crystal Phylactery#0 could make it function again...</desc>
		<relatedEntries>otherworldly_aura,blackaurem_structure,crystal_phylactery</relatedEntries>
	</block>
  </blocks>
  <mechanics>
    <mechanic id="affinity">
      <name>Affinities</name>
      <desc>#5Affinity#0 represents a bond to certain areas of magic.  You start with no affinity.  Your affinity is represented as a small chart on the HUD, and can be viewed in more detail at an Occulus (craftable Block).  Your affinity will shift based on what spells you cast, meaning as you cast certain types of spells more often, you will get better at them.
			Casting spells of a differing affinity will shift you towards that affinity.  Once you reach 100% in an affinity, you become locked to that affinity, and will need to read an opposing affinity tome to unlock your affinity, at which point normal progression will resume.  Unlocking a full affinity will drop you down to 80% depth.
			
			Each spell component has an affinity.  Components of the same affinity as you will cost less mana, and depending on your affinity depth (how far into the affinity you are), may not even cost reagents.  Components of the opposing affinity, however, will cost more mana and again, depending on your affinity depth, may cost additional reagents.  Affinities offer specific bonuses and disadvantages, described on the affinity-specific pages.			
			</desc>
      <subitem id="earth_affinity">
        <name>Earth Affinity</name>
        <desc>
					Earth affinity grants a minor defense bonus, due to your hardened skin.  At max, you will have 10% overall damage reduction, applied before armor.  This amount depends on your affinity depth into earth, and begins at 25% depth.
					!d
					With earth affinity, you are heavier, and as such you will sink more quickly in water (though never enough that you cannot surface), and you cannot fall as far without taking fall damage.
				</desc>
        <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="water_affinity">
        <name>Water Affinity</name>
        <desc>
					Water affinity grants a bonus to swim speed as well as slower breath loss underwater.  You are also not pushed by flowing water.  Endermen that attack a full water-affinity mage will take damage as if they had touched water.
					!d
					Water affinity mages take damage periodically if exposed to fire, making the nether particularly dangerous.  This damage will not take you below 75% health, and will not occur at all if you are lower.
				</desc>
        <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="air_affinity">
        <name>Air Affinity</name>
        <desc>
					Air affinity grants a bonus to jump height and lets you fall farther before taking damage.  These bonuses are dependent on your affinity depth: you can jump one block higher and fall one block farther at 50% depth.  This bonus increases to 2 at 75%, and 3 at full depth.
					!d
					Air affinity mages are hindered by rain and storms; the wind blows you around and you must move slower.  #5Sneaking#0 or casting a spell of #5Gravity Well#0 can negate the effect and allow you to move in the storm, albeit slowly.
				</desc>
        <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="fire_affinity">
        <name>Fire Affinity</name>
        <desc>
					Fire affinity grants damage reduction in fire and lava, though never complete immunity.  The protection is directly related to your affinity depth, and reaches 60% reduction at full depth.  Punching enemies at full affinity will light them on fire.
					!d
					Once your fire affinity reaches 50%, you will start to take damage periodically when touching water sources.  This damage will not take you down below 75% health and will not occur if lower.
				</desc>
        <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="nature_affinity">
        <name>Nature Affinity</name>
        <desc>
					Nature affinity gives you additional seeds and saplings when harvesting plants from around the world.  At 50% depth, you will gain the Thorns effect, causing melee attackers to take damage (similar to the armor enchant).  This damage increases at 75% affinity and at full affinity.  At full nature affinity you also slowly regenerate hunger in direct sunlight.  At full nature affinity, you can extend roots into the ground, allowing you to climb certain surfaces like a spider does.
					!d
					Nature affinity causes you to move slightly slower due to your roots. At full nature affinity depth, you lose hunger more quickly at night or in dark areas.
					!d
					At full nature affinity, you gain the aspect of a leaf on the wind, negating all fall damage and falling more slowly.  You can sneak to fall at normal speed.  This will still cause fall damage to be negated.
				</desc>
        <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="ice_affinity">
        <name>Ice Affinity</name>
        <desc>
					Ice affinity causes attackers to be slowed.  At 50% depth, while sneaking you will freeze water to ice in front of you, allowing you to make bridges as you move.  At 100% depth, you can freeze lava to obsidian.
					!d
					All ice mages move slightly slower due to being cold blooded, unless on ice or water.
				</desc>
        <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="lightning_affinity">
        <name>Lightning Affinity</name>
        <desc>
					Lightning affinity causes you to run faster.  The speed increase is directly related to your affinity depth, ranging from 1 to 30%.  At 50% depth, you gain the ability to step up over one block high ledges.
					!d
					Unfortunately due to your affinity you are also sort of short out in water. You can also light nearby TNT and supercharge nearby creepers!  Don't worry though, as you gain more control over your electric nature, you will be able to reduce the TNT and Creeper effects.
				</desc>
        <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="life_affinity">
        <name>Life Affinity</name>
        <desc>
					Life affinity causes you to very slowly regenerate additional life.  The regen speed is directly related to your depth.  This regen happens regardless of your hunger level.
					!d
					Due to your close ties with life, any time you kill something it makes you sick and nauseated for a while.
				</desc>
        <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="arcane_affinity">
        <name>Arcane Affinity</name>
        <desc>
					Arcane affinity causes all spells to cost 5% less mana, in addition to other mana reductions.  At full depth, there is also a chance that upon casting a spell, you will gain the clarity effect, causing your next spell to cost 0 mana.
					!d
					As a disadvantage, all magical damage sources do more damage to you.
				</desc>
        <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="ender_affinity">
        <name>Ender Affinity</name>
        <desc>
					Ender affinity gives you poison resistance at 50% depth, and at 75% depth you gain night vision automatically in dark areas.  At full ender affinity, Endermen will not attack you, unless you attack them first.
					!d
					Due to your dark nature, your maximum health is reduced in light, and at higher ender affinity, it is reduced in water as well.  Masters of the ender are rumored to have evolved beyond this weakness.
				</desc>
        <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </mechanic>
    <mechanic id="spellCreation" unlocked="true">
      <name>Spell Creation</name>
      <desc>Creating spells is somewhat time consuming, but simple.  First, learn some spell parts using an #5Occulus#0.  Next, lay out the spell you want to create at an #5Inscription Table#0.  Place the book from the inscription table on the lectern of your crafting altar structure, and throw in a #5Blank Rune#0.  The book will guide you through the rest of the process, showing you what you need.  When Etherium is required during the spell creation process, use a #5crystal wrench#0 to change the power type if necessary, then flip the switch on the multiblock.  The structure will draw enough power, then turn the switch off automatically.  Once your spell is created, equip it and right click to name it and set the icon.  Once you have done this correctly, the spell will be castable!  Otherwise it will show the customization UI again when you cast.</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </mechanic>
    <mechanic id="infusion">
      <name>Infusion</name>
      <desc>#5Infusion#0 is a process in which AM armor will drain mana from your mana pool to repair itself.  Due to this mechanic, all AM armor has low durability, and won't last in a prolonged fight.  Taking the armor off will cause it to stop infusing - it must be equipped for the mechanic to function.  If the armor is at full durability, there is no mana cost.</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </mechanic>
    <mechanic id="mana" unlocked="true">
      <name>Mana</name>
      <desc>Mana is your magical energy level.  You gain more mana by increasing your Magic Level. !d Mana regenerates over time, but you can gain boosts to regeneration by eating a #9Mana Cake#0 or standing near an Obelisk, Celestial Prism, or Black Aurem with more than 10% charge.  #9Mana Potions#0 and #9Mana Potion Bundles#0 can be used to give an instant boost to mana.  Mana is represented by a blue bar on your HUD.  You can use "#2/amuicfg#0" to toggle an option to show the actual numeric values of your mana.</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </mechanic>
    <mechanic id="magicLevel" unlocked="true">
      <name>Magic Level</name>
      <desc>Magic Level represents your strength as a mage.  As your Magic Level increases, so will your Mana and Burnout capacities.  Magic level can be increased by casting valid spells.  A valid spell cast is one that does what is intended, meaning casting fire bolt at a wall for an hour won't get you anywhere.  Certain components that have valid targets more rarely award more magical XP towards the next level.  Your Magic Level is represented by a blue number on your HUD.  You can use "#2/amuicfg#0" to toggle an option to show the actual numeric values of your magic XP bar.</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </mechanic>
    <mechanic id="burnout" unlocked="true">
      <name>Burnout</name>
      <desc>Burnout is your level of strain when casting spells.  The higher your Burnout, the more mana each spell will cost.  Casting more powerful spells will cause more Burnout.  It will decrease over time.  Gaining Magic Levels will give you a higher Burnout cap, allowing you to cast more spells before becoming completely fatigued.  Your Burnout level is displayed as a red bar on the HUD.  You can use "#2/amuicfg#0" to toggle an option to show the actual numeric values of your burnout.</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </mechanic>
    <mechanic id="rituals">
      <name>Summoning Rituals</name>
      <desc>Summoning Rituals are what are performed to call upon bosses in Ars Magica.  See the #5bosses section#0 of this compendium for the rituals specific to each boss.</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </mechanic>
    <mechanic id="moonstone_meteors">
      <name>Moonstone Meteors</name>
      <desc>On occasion, during the night, small meteors may crash down into the overworld.  This is the only way to obtain moonstone ore.  A full moon increases the odds of one spawning.  The meteor always falls within 32 blocks of a player, and they will only ever fall on a biome's cover block.  Meaning unless you have a house made of grass, it won't even hit your home.  If you do have a house made of grass, then what is wrong with you?  Didn't you ever read the three little pigs?</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </mechanic>
    <mechanic id="enchantments" unlocked="true">
      <name>Enchantments</name>
      <desc>AM adds a few useful enchantments to the game to assist in your ascent to magical mastery.</desc>
      <subitem id="magic_resistance">
        <name>Magic Resistance</name>
        <desc>As the name suggests, this enchant offers protection against magic damage.  There are 4 ranks to the enchantment, and it goes on armor.</desc>
        <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <subitem id="soulbound">
        <name>Soulbound</name>
        <desc>Ever get tired of losing your gear on death?  You can fix that now.  The soulbound enchant can be applied to just about any item that accepts enchantments, and will cause that item to remain in your inventory on death.  You will respawn with the item in the same slot in your inventory it was when you died.  Soulbound has a max enchantment level of 1.</desc>
        <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
      </subitem>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </mechanic>
    <mechanic id="armor_xp_infusion">
      <name>Armor XP Infusion</name>
      <desc>Whenever you gain XP, any equipped armor will gain some too.  The amount gained is equal to the total amount of XP you just gained divided evenly among all equipped armor pieces.  Any armor can gain XP.  Stored armor XP can be used at an #9Armor Imbuement Table#0.</desc>
      <relatedEntries>armor_infuser</relatedEntries>
    </mechanic>
    <mechanic id="silver_skills">
      <name>Silver Skills</name>
      <desc>Silver skills are skills inside the occulus that cannot be obtained in normal ways.  To unlock a silver skill, the correct spell combination must be crafted, and then cast.  There are a few rules to silver skill unlock combinations that will make them somewhat easier to decipher. !d 1.) All parts required to unlock a silver skill will be in the #9same tree as the silver skill itself#0. !d 2.) All silver skills require between #9 2 and 4 components and/or modifiers to unlock#0. !d 3.) Shapes do not matter in unlocking a silver skill.  #9Any shape can be used#0. !d 4.) The combination #9does not have to be in any specific order#0.  As long as the correct components are present, it will work. !d 5.) The components/modifiers #9all have to be in the same stage#0. !d 6.) The components and modifiers #9will logcally make sense with the silver skill#0.  For example, Firestorm won't require drown. !d 7.) The spell to unlocka silver skill may not be the most practical for common use.</desc>
      <relatedEntries></relatedEntries>
    </mechanic>
  </mechanics>
  <guides>
    <guide id="introToArsMagica" order="0" unlocked="true" new="false">
      <name>Foreword</name>
      <desc>Ars Magica began as my first foray into modding.  I have been developing software professionally for about 11 years as of AM2's release, but haven't done much game design.  I loved the game of Minecraft, but felt that it would be the perfect place for a magical world.  So I began, and who would have thought I would enjoy it so much.  I have spent literally hundreds of hours developing AM1 and AM2.  With some good tutorials and a bit of luck, I managed to figure out how to write AM1.  Now I have taken what I learned, solved some of the problems that came up (and probably introduced twice as many more), and have made Ars Magica 2.  I want to thank all of the people who helped this mod come to be what it is today, my beta testers, everyone who helped me with code, models, and texturing - this wouldn't be what it is without you.  And to you, the player, I hope that you have as much fun playing this mod as I did making it. !d Happy Casting! !l ~Mithion</desc>
    </guide>
    <guide id="usingThisCompendium" order="1" unlocked="true">
      <name>Using this Compendium</name>
      <desc>This compendium is set up to unlock entries as you get to them, to somewhat guide you through the getting started process of the mod.  You will be notified when you unlock a new entry.  Categories with new items in them will shimmer, and new entries themselves will have a crescent moon marking them as new.  !d If you prefer to not have this, you can disable it in config by changing "Staged Compendium" to false.  This compendium is #9intra-linking#0.  Any item you hover over that has green text can be clicked and you will jump to the entry for that item. !d This compendium also leaves a breadcrumb trail, meaning you can step back through in reverse order through pages you have visited.</desc>
    </guide>
    <guide id="theAMUI" order="2" unlocked="true">
      <name>The Ars Magica UI</name>
      <desc>The act of picking up a compendium has unlocked the arcane magics within you.  You now have the AM2 HUD activated.  To configure this UI, at any time, enter the command "#2/amuicfg#0".  This will open a drag and drop configuration interface.  Make your changes and press ESC to save them.</desc>
    </guide>
    <guide id="spellComponents101" order="5">
      <name>Spell Components 101</name>
      <desc>Spells are comprised of #4shapes#0, #9components#0, and #2modifiers#0.  Shapes dictate how the spell targets things, Components dictate what the spell does to the things it targets, and Modifiers change certain aspects of spells.  A #4shape#0 can only appear once in a single spell.  Shapes can be chained together to create spell stages, for example, a "Projectile AoE".  Components can be added once per spell stage. As for modifiers, a single aspect of a spell can be modified three times per stage.  What this means is that if you have modifiers that change multiple parts of a spell, they may lock out other ones that modify the same stats if the total stat modifier for the shape is equal to three.  The compendium will only show you the shapes, components, and modifiers you already know, or are eligible to learn.</desc>
    </guide>
    <guide id="yourFirstSpell" order="3" unlocked="true">
      <name>Your First Spell</name>
      <desc>To make a spell, you will first need to create an #5Occulus#0 and unlock at least one spell shape and one component.  You start with three blue skill points to make this possible.  Then, craft a writable book and head over to your #5Inscription Table#0.  Place the book in the inscription table. !d There are three sections of the Inscription Table UI that are of note.  The source region is the large grey square at the top, and will contain all of your known shapes, components, and modifiers.  The Shape Group section is identified by brown squares.  There are multiple brown squares as multiple shape groups can be created.  Finally there is the Spell Grammar section, which is the gray rectangle at the bottom.  !d Create #5Shape Groups#0 by dragging shapes and/or modifiers from the source region to any of the shape groups in the UI.  You can create multiple shape groups in the same spell, three by default.  Each shape group can have up to four shapes/modifiers.  Shape groups cannot contain components. A good way to think about it is that shape groups are different means of targeting things with the spell, then the spell grammar is what the spell actually does. !d Once your shape groups are created, drag the spell parts you want, in order, from the source region to the spell grammar section. The spell grammar section can contain spell shapes, components, and modifiers in addition to the shape groups.  Once your combination is completed, go to your #5Crafting Altar#0 and place your book containing the spell recipe on the lectern.  Throw a #5blank rune#0 into the middle of the crafting altar to begin the process, then follow the book's prompts.  The book itself is worth reading as well, as it contains a recap of what the spell recipe is for, the materials list for the spell and an affinity breakdown of the spell.  Note that certain crafting altars can only craft spells that are so powerful.  Too much power and bad things can happen.  See the entry on the #5Crafting Altar#0 for more information.</desc>
    </guide>
	<guide id="aFewSpells" order="4" unlocked="true">
      <name>A Few Recommended Spells</name>
      <desc>When starting out, it's recommended to make sure you take at least one #9Shape#0 and one #9Component#0 in the Occulus, lest you find yourself unable to make any spells.  If you do this, you can either go looking in dungeons for #9Infinity Orbs#0, or try to fight a boss or two to get some more.  If you're feeling cheaty, you can also use the /respec command. !p Here are a few sample spells to get you started: !d Basic Defense: !l Projectile + Physical Damage !d Stay Alive: !l Self + Regeneration !d Time to Mine: !l Touch/Projectile + Dig !d Clear Leaves: !l Projectile + Wizard's Autumn !d Fast Travel: !l Self/Projectile + Leap + Slowfall + Haste + Gravity Well</desc>
    </guide>
    <guide id="gainingMagicLevels" order="6">
      <name>Gaining Magic Levels</name>
      <desc>You gain magic levels by casting spells.  You don't gain magic XP if the cast isn't successful, and there are diminishing returns on a cooldown, so spamming spells to grind won't get you anywhere.  Casting spells also modifies your affinity.  See #5Mechanics -&gt; Affinity#0 for more information.</desc>
    </guide>
    <guide id="unlockingPowers" order="7">
      <name>Obtaining Skill Points</name>
      <desc>You get skill points primarily by leveling up.  At each even level, you will gain one skill point.  Levels 2-20 award blue skill points, 22-40 award green skill points, and 42-50 award red skill points.  Additional points can be obtained by fighting bosses, trading with villagers, and exploring.  You choose how you want to go about it!  When viewing unlockables in the #5Occulus#0, hovering over the item will display #9text that matches the skill point color needed to unlock it#0.</desc>
    </guide>
    <guide id="essenceAllAround" order="8">
      <name>The Etherium System</name>
      <desc>Ars Magica contains a unique power system called #5Etherium#0.  Etherium is generated from an #5Obelisk#0.  An Obelisk will stream to other powered blocks within a 10 block radius.  To extend the range of the Obelisk, you can place #5Etherium Conduits#0 within the 10 blocks of the obelisk.  Each conduit also projects a radius of 10 blocks in which it can relay power from the obelisk, essentially extending the range in a chain. !d There are multiple types of Etherium.  Different types of Etherium can be generated by other blocks, suck as #9Light Etherium#0 from a #5Celestial Prism#0 or #4Dark Etherium#0 from a #5Black Aurem#0.  All Etherium types have the same transmit rules as the Obelisk, and can be extended by Etherium Conduits.</desc>
    </guide>
    <guide id="powerTypes" order="9">
      <name>Types of Etherium</name>
      <desc>There are three types of Etherium, by default.  Addons to the mod can register new Etherium types, but the defaults are Light, Neutral, and Dark.  See structures for crafting and variations of each of these.  Each type of Etherium affects machines in a different way, and has advantages and disadvantages.  You will also need all three types of Etherium available for spell crafting, as certain shapes, components, and modifiers can require different types of Etherium.  Certain machines can only run on certain types of Etherium, and some machines require multiple types simultaneously.</desc>
    </guide>
  </guides>
</compendium>
